Hello and welcome to the Junkyard Love Podcast.
Hello and welcome aliens and alienates and humans and primates and zombies and whatever
else you may be listening to this.
This is the Junkyard Love Podcast.
I'm Jake Reigns and today we've got a wonderful conversation with my wonderful friend Jay.
It's super awesome.
Can't wait to get to it.
Before real quick, I'm going to give you a recommendation.
I like to give a little recommendation for the podcast to get going.
This week's is going to be Why Good Leaders Make You Feel Safe by Simon Sinek.
It's on YouTube.
It's a TED talk.
It's 12 minutes long.
It's fantastic.
Check it out.
Enjoy the rest of your day.
Also, real quick, before the conversation gets going, breathe out slowly and just be
present.
Remember where you're at.
Slow down, let go of your shoulders, relax.
Everything's all right.
All right.
Enjoy the comment.
I feel like famous.
You are famous today.
I know it feels so official to just have headphones on and you're like, this microphone is for
me.
I got to talk into it.
No, I like it.
It's nice.
Hello, Jay.
Welcome to the Junkyard Love Podcast.
Hi.
Thank you.
I feel so honored to actually be here.
Yeah.
I feel honored that you would come on and just talk about yourself and share some
cool stuff.
Just because it's right here and we were talking about it briefly, let's just
start with Chakras.
You want to just let's say that I'm a total dummy and I don't know anything
about Chakras.
I know a little bit, but I just want to say that I kind of don't too.
But you know like a little bit?
Yeah.
I understand the concept, but because you know with a lot of the stuff that I learned
about when I do yoga, yoga for me for example, wasn't like a series of going through trainings
and like going to a lot of classes where people taught, it was just kind of like
clicking around through YouTube and like I would stretch and like, okay, my fingers
can touch the floor and it feels good to lift my hand up and these sort of
things.
I love the explanations like when people talk about Chakras.
I love that I'm so open to it now.
Yeah.
Well, it's you.
Right.
Yeah.
It starts making sense.
It's so funny.
I feel like before I would be very like deflective like I'm like, get that away from
I don't know what that is.
Like get that away.
I don't know what you're talking about.
Like I don't want to hear it, you know.
And when you just listen, it's like, oh, it makes sense.
Yeah.
Well, it's interesting.
Like I feel like when you're not ready to hear about it, it's
because you're not ready to heal.
So when you start learning about Chakras, you're ready to start healing them.
Right.
So I'm not an expert by any means, but I actually like got them tattooed on my back
when I was 18 and I just feel like Chakras like, oh my gosh, it makes sense.
So basically there's a bunch, but there's like the seven main ones and their wheels.
So think of them as like spinning wheels.
So if you can imagine that one is blocked and you try to pour water in the top like
wheels of water and one is blocked, right?
How is it going to get the water going to get down?
It's going to be blocked.
So think about that with energy.
So think people who have like I start like my throat chakra is like closing up talking
now, but think about like people who can give love, but they can't receive love.
I'm one of those people.
So I'll have back pain in between my shoulder blades.
Like someone's pushing their palm between my blades.
So the chakra is in the back is for receiving, which is blocked so much of my life where I'm
pushing out through my front heart.
I can give love, I can give love, but then I'm not receiving any.
So it's like love's going out, but love can't come in.
So it's literally physically causing symptoms in my body.
Right.
That tightness.
And that's because my back chakra is open because I can't receive, but when
I'm like I is so easy to open your shockers and that's why I love them because
I can just say I'm open to receiving love and I can just envision like green and it opens.
So do you?
Okay.
So your back chakra, for example, is that the color that affiliates?
Yeah.
So I can go over them from the beginning.
No, you're fine.
We can dance around.
It's no big deal.
So for this example, when you're saying it's blocked, like I feel this pain
in my back, like can you sit down and do you, do you treat this as a meditation
or do you just like, so you set aside a couple of minutes and you just get your thoughts
like, okay, what is that, that feeling?
Yeah.
So do you just focus on the spot itself?
I do kind of both.
So it's like, I know I didn't like exercise my back.
So it's like, why does my back hurt?
And I just actually learned in the chakra class that a lot of healers close off their
receiving because they're not good enough or they don't think they should receive,
which is something I struggle with my whole life is receiving is so hard for me.
It's like, what?
You want to do something nice for me?
I don't deserve that because of that inner child, right?
Like, I don't deserve this because our parents made us feel like that or other
people.
So I just, what I would do is I would like sit and I'll actually have like certain
stones for it.
But and I just envision like green and like opening it up.
And I actually think of like a wheel and like opening it up and you can like even
like move your hand like counterclockwise in front of your heart to clear the
gunk. And then you can move your other hand clockwise to put good energy in.
And it's so easy like anyone can do it.
Like you don't have to be a healer.
Yeah, it's it's it's funny.
We we think of like, why would you do that?
And but if you if you just try it, I mean, definitely, I definitely agree.
If you just try these things, I love following all these just on YouTube,
like visualizations.
They'll have things of that same manner.
I listened to one the other day that it made your all of your chakras.
You imagine them as different flowers.
Yeah.
Oh man.
And just it felt wonderful.
It's just sometimes for me, like I'll be like, how do you even
realize I was blocked in this area?
Or I wasn't didn't realize I had some tightness in this area.
And then you do one of those and it seems to help out.
Yeah.
So as I was like, kind of prepping for today, because I feel like chakras
are something that anyone and everyone should know about.
So basically, there's like seven main ones.
So there's like the root, which is red.
It's like kind of in the lower like area.
And then it goes up to like the sacral, which is like your sexuality.
It's an orange color.
And then you go up to your solar, which is like your stomach, your womb.
If you're female, like, you know, and it's like your power center.
And then you go up to your heart.
It's more green.
It can also be pink.
You go up to your throat.
It's blue.
Go up to your third eye and then your crown, right?
So I just thought it was interesting because this is me.
So if you have a like solar plexus imbalance, which is like yellow,
you're addicted to food, caffeine, starches,
detailed and compulsive cleaning.
So you can see what chakras are blocked in like common addictions.
Right.
And it's like, whoa, like I would love potatoes and coffee
and like compulsive and cleaning.
Yeah, it speaks to you.
And like my solar plexus is in balance and I know that.
And so what do you do?
So you're like, OK, I know, I recognize these things.
Like those are totally me not speaking to me.
What's your what's your step there?
Like you're like, OK, do I need I can't just obviously I'm addicted to these.
You know, I want these starchy foods.
I want this caffeine.
Like what do you do to help balance those things?
So I actually like today I'm having coffee, but I actually quit drinking coffee
because I'm like, I'm not going to let a substance rule me.
I when you start, I feel when you have discipline over what you eat,
you have discipline over your whole life.
Mm hmm. I feel that personally.
Food is such like a trigger for so many people.
Like there's a bull M&M's like, who isn't going to try to eat one
or who has that discipline to just sit there and go, no, my body doesn't want that.
Right. You know what I mean?
Yeah, I have a Shailene and I are on run.
I think excuse me.
I think we're on day 20 or so of Whole 30 again.
I love that.
Yeah, we have this is my third time doing it.
And I think that every time I do it, I feel a little tougher.
I feel a little stronger.
I feel a little like, I mean, of course, I feel fantastic just by, you know,
not eating inherently.
I, I having the podcast, I've had people come over and we'll go,
like have a beer after we're go, you know, have some, some food afterwards.
So I was getting carried away with that, but just resetting and like knowing
like me, because I can tell, like, OK, you know, my stomach's not feeling great,
you know, and you could follow it.
You know why, you know, so it's good to explore and like, all right,
I'm going to take a break for me and you with caffeine.
Like you're like, it's not helping me sometimes, you know, and it's nice
and it's comforting and I work at a coffee shop.
Like I love coffee and I think it like brightens people's day.
But when it's I need coffee, that's when it's a problem to me.
I need to eat potatoes tonight.
Like that's where it's like my energies imbalanced because I don't need
anything but love, right?
But like, so I'm seeing that and I'm recognizing it and then it also
stems to like, so that's like your power center.
So it's like, I am good enough, I am enough.
I've been working on that lately, too, where I don't like I've been
like trying to apply to the hospital.
Like I'm I have my bachelor's degree in nursing, but I work at a coffee shop,
you know, and it's like this internal like I'm not good enough
to work in the hospital.
I'm not smart enough.
I don't know enough.
And that's that chakra.
OK, so it's like to really just like work on it.
But like, it's really easy to just do all of them.
I have a pendulum and like moving.
But you can just open it with meditation or with fasting.
I love to fast water and just cleanse and let your body reset
or go out in nature and just reconnect.
Yeah, but you can heal them really fast.
And a lot of people will have chronic blockages and all physical
ailments come from chakra imbalances.
It starts in the or field chakra imbalance, emotional imbalance,
physical imbalance.
OK, so OK, so a lot of nurses get sick.
A lot of doctors get sick.
A lot of healthy people can get sick.
Why I'm so healthy because they're working with sick people
and that energy is coming into their auric field and they don't
know how to cleanse it because they're not right.
And they're getting sick.
I think that I think that a lot of our the world we live in
is so disconnected from the body, you know?
I mean, where it's something.
So even me, I've always been athletic, I've always worked out.
But I always had, you know, like like my arm looks tight in this shirt.
But like, if it gets too tight around my belly, like, oh,
I'm super self conscious about it, these sort of things.
But like, and now, you know, I do yoga and I don't really care
about how I look, it's about how I feel.
And it's this like this shift.
I feel like when you're so obsessed about how you look, you're almost like,
you know, say, say, you know, you have a belly right now.
You're like, oh, I've been eating too much or whatever.
The the discontent, the
non connected feelings that you send that area of your body.
Well, the thing is to the more when I'm focused on, oh, how overweight I am,
I'm going to stay overweight because that's what I'm telling my body.
I am. Right.
If I look at my body and I say, thank you for food.
I'm glad I'm full, right?
Because some people are starving.
So instead of looking at your body as like discussed and oh, I'm overweight.
How about you say, I have the best body.
I have a six pack or I can run.
I'm healthy.
I can breathe like so many people can't walk.
So many people can't even feed themselves.
So many people don't have food.
So shift that mindset into being like, wow, thank you.
Maybe I have a belly, but at least I'm not starving.
And to kind of just shift your mind that people would love to have that.
Yeah. Right.
Like shift your mindset and be like, maybe this isn't where I want to be at.
But envision yourself like, oh, I really want to like I'm overweight.
Like I swear, like every time I'm in that mindset, I stay overweight.
Even if I'm working out, eating good.
I'm like, I'm not losing weight because you're saying that.
Right. You are your commander.
Right. Like your body follows and like your subconscious doesn't know like the difference.
Yeah. You got to train your subconscious.
I always say that.
Like, you know, your subconscious is running things 95% of the time.
And like when you can find that 5%, well, yeah.
But when you can find that, we're like, OK, I'm noticing that I'm running on autopilot.
Then I can insert these other thoughts in there.
And, you know, and so instead of if you're feeling these feelings of shame
listener or, you know, like, oh, I'm overweight or I'm this and you can't
seem to like connect with what does this have to do with other people?
Just I think just stop and think of the benefit of the way that you're thinking
or the disbenefit rather of the way that you're thinking.
Like does this lead you to healing?
Does this lead you to feeling better?
A lot of times we feel something and we think we have to just feel it forever.
Like that's me. I have this overweight, sad feeling in my belly.
And that's me forever.
That's just who I am.
And then anybody who tries to come at it, you just stab them with your sword
and they, you know, you protect yourself from it.
We all have those things.
Yeah. Well, Jay, I definitely want to talk about
well, actually, let's back up your name, even we were talking about your name.
I know, but I have said it a couple of times.
Let's get your your full name that you have like to be called now
that you've grown older.
My full name is actually Jordan now.
I feel we're kind of talking about this earlier, but I feel like
I like grew into my name.
You know, I didn't start really start using it until I went to college
and I was rushing for my sorority and it was printed right there.
I'm like, I can't hide it now.
It's there.
And then a lot of times people like don't want to call me.
I go, is there anything?
It's too long or it's still and it's like, yeah, call me Jay.
I don't know, just started happening when I was little.
And then or Jordy or Jordan or.
Simplified for other people.
Whatever names like I'm like, call me whatever.
Because some people are like, you know, when people get
Starbucks drinks and they spell their name wrong, they're so offended.
That's so weird.
Isn't it?
I'm like, why does it bother you so much?
It's like a trigger that says, wait, people love this picture
about it all the time.
I'm like, first of all, like they're stressed.
Like, is it really a big deal that they spell your name wrong?
I think that's what they're thinking about.
And that's what you're supposed to.
I mean, yeah, we have this weird thing with our name.
Like, if someone called me the wrong name, I don't correct.
Like, I'm like, but I'm very passive.
Like, I'll let someone call me the wrong name for a long time.
Like, I really am so passive.
I'm like, I just hate conflict so much that I'm like, sorry.
But other people are like, no, my name, like they're really
like into their power, though.
And I used to get mad at those people, but I was mad
because there's a trigger, because I wasn't like that.
Oh, because you weren't standing up for yourself?
Yeah, yeah.
Because it's like, you know, when you are upset, I always
talk about this, like on my personal Instagram, like if
someone is doing something and it bothers you, there's
a reason for that.
And that shit's going to keep happening until it doesn't
bother you anymore, because eventually that same
stuff's going to happen and you're not even noticing it
because it doesn't bother you.
Once you work on your triggers, they just, there's less.
You notice that you don't really care what other
people are doing.
No, and people don't care what you're doing.
Yeah, we always talk about that.
A good example, like say you, you take the garbage
out to the curb, right?
And you're like, you're in your pajama pants
and sandals and you're like, oh man, my neighbors
are going to think that I'm a total scrub.
It's like, your neighbors don't even know you exist right now.
They don't care where they're like, that guy is putting
his garbage out to the curb.
If they even think that, they probably will literally
just see it and not even let the full thought
come into their mind.
They're so not caring about what you're doing, you know?
I feel that, like, you know, I'm like the
crazy, I'm like going out full moons, like collecting
rainwater and cleansing my rocks.
I'm like, people, my partner's like, no one
cares what you're doing.
They might be looking at you because they're curious,
but they're not like, no one cares what you're doing.
Yeah, they're like, let go.
Yeah, I love that.
That's great.
I mean, that's, you know, I'm happy to have you
on this podcast because, you know, that's my whole
thing here is that everybody has something to teach
you, knowledge is power, like in just being open
to like, hey, like what, like, what do you think
about this whole thing we got going on?
You know, like, because, you know, a lot of us
have read the same, the same books in school
and we've been raised in the same areas.
And so there's a lot of stuff that we know
similar, right?
And we do find things that are different about
each other and we kind of poke at them because
we're, we're uncomfortable, but I don't like that.
I, I like finding things.
Make me uncomfortable.
Right.
Yeah, I just like finding things about people
like, oh, I don't know, I just being so open
to new experiences in new ways of thinking
about life because when you're open to it,
it seems like it's like, oh, my life
is now improving in this way or if something
isn't working out for you, maybe there's a
belief around that that you have that could be
like changed, you know, you don't, I think
just, just allowing people to, to open up
and be themselves.
Be authentic.
Yeah.
And because, because I, like I said, I, you know,
I have a lot of last couple of years, the
spirituality thing is new for me.
And so like I said, I was telling you, like,
I find myself going to your Instagram.
Oh my gosh, that makes me want to cry.
No, it's great because these are things
that like, I'm like, I don't know,
I don't know about that, but it seems
like it kind of makes sense to me.
And it feels right.
And I experienced this thing.
Yeah, it definitely resonates with me.
And then so having these things where
you can kind of get answers or feel like
there's someone else who's connecting with you.
That's what it's all about.
I think just realizing that everybody has
a different way of seeing things, but
there's so many similarities and there's
so many ways that like, you don't have
to stay the same.
You could be like, hey, like, like, like
Jordan else said this thing, then like,
it was just profound to me.
I've never even thought about it before,
but now like, I'm going to try that
shit tomorrow, you know, why not?
What the world is for, I think.
And I think it's very healing to learn
and just try new things.
And I think like for me,
I've always just kind of, I mean,
I've always really been comfortable.
Like I've never been the girl that wear
makeup, not against wearing makeup at all,
but I've always just been me.
Like I can wake up and go like
because I am who I am.
You know what I mean?
And I feel like so many of us are like
just scared to show up for ourselves,
scared to look in the mirror.
You know, like how like, why can't you?
Like who's making you feel less than
it's yourself and like, why can't you
just like be authentic for you?
And I'm telling you when you're authentic
for you, your life just
the right door is open.
Because what I was doing is I'm such a
people pleaser, I don't eat meat.
So like, I remember this coffee shop,
this guy's a hunter and he's like,
want to see what I killed?
And I'm like being passive.
I'm like, yeah, but no, I don't.
Okay.
But you know what I mean?
So like that's for me where it's
like, when you engage in conversations
that you don't like, you are creating
false energy cords with these people
and false attachments.
And I just heard the other day,
it's better to be respected than loved,
which is huge for me.
I like that because like I am so like,
yes, like, yes, like, like I just
like want everyone to be comfortable
and happy, but it's like, you need
to say no, no is so powerful.
And that's like my biggest lesson is
like, no, I don't want to do that.
And I don't need to explain myself.
But yeah, when it comes to self love,
you know, that's such a bus feed word
at this point, you know, sometimes
you'll be a little confusing.
What does that mean?
You know, there's a million different,
you know, what does it mean to you
is what it is.
But a lot of a lot of saying no
is self love, seriously.
And like, you know, when you start
just like a history, I've been
on my spiritual journey for about 11 years.
I started really meditating
and diving into it about five years ago.
But I want I wanted to come on here
and say that you don't just wake up
in one day and you don't just wake up
and you're happy.
Like it's been a lot of shadow self
and a lot of dark days.
It's not all incense and crystals
and like love yourself.
Like it's really not all like that.
Like, yeah, I'm like that on my Instagram
because that's how I want my
followers to be encouraged.
But I also want them to know
that like in who's listening,
that it doesn't happen overnight
and it's work because you have to dig
deep and like see your childhood
self and like outside influences
and like heal.
But when you start healing your
memories, it actually rewires
the future because you can change
your like a bad experience.
Look at it in a different way.
Yeah.
And it rewires your DNA.
It absolutely does.
You can look at it instead
of experiencing it as the sufferer
that you were.
You can look at it from the
witness perspective of a 20
something year old person who is
like, OK, this thing happened to me.
What about it?
Like, let's let's look at it.
What really happened and what's
different now?
How can I perceive it differently
than my childhood self did?
Yeah, and like how I know
people have healed is because
like I'm like dig into your trauma
as a child if they can't even talk
or they start crying like their
throat shock or they have not done
the work.
Right.
Like when I first started opening up
about like my childhood, because I
had like to me, I had a traumatic
childhood, but now I don't see it
like that.
But if I were to tell you my story,
you'd be like, how are you?
How are you this way when you
didn't have anything?
So I think it's really important
to just realize that also like,
don't I talk about this?
Don't compare trauma like I see
people doing that where it's like,
well, this happened to me.
So I should be more messed up or
like this didn't happen to you.
You had a great life.
Well, you don't know how they
perceived it.
Like just because they had two
parents and they had money doesn't
mean that they had a great life as
an individual.
And that's so important to know
because we often compare like, oh,
I didn't have a parent or my
parents died or like there's so
much like comparing of our
lives to like justify how we
act, but just own up to
like it.
Yeah, yeah, it doesn't make sense
to compare because it's like
I've used this this example
before like you could be
terrified of snakes today
because when you were six, not
you got bit by a snake, but a man
who was wearing a snake shirt
yelled at you.
I mean, like that's
you know, that that's a short
extension of the word childhood
trauma. But but I feel like we do
hear words and sentences
like childhood trauma very often
in its when you start learning
more about it.
There's so much to it.
Like the aces, right?
Have you heard of the aces,
right? Like the 10 questions?
Oh, no, hit me with them.
Do you remember?
I don't know them all off
hand, but it's like a parents
in a jail.
You've been like sexually
assaulted.
One of your more parents was a
substance abuser.
There's like all the things that
like things that like trauma
and it actually I
I'm 10 out of 10, by the way,
which is like the highest score
you can get.
And I'm predicted to not go to
school and predicted like and
it's crazy because it's
showing that trauma
can change your DNA in this
lifetime.
They're literally seeing at a
molecular level that these
trauma is changing your DNA
and also trauma is passed
down.
And we are the generation
to heal that ancestral
trauma and stop it.
I absolutely believe that, too.
No more of it.
We are not our grandparents.
Yeah, we are not our parents
even. There's a
you know, in a jumping to like
culture society, sometimes I
feel like right now
you know, a lot of a lot of our
job, like my job, for example,
like I'm a good moderator, I
would say I'm good at having
two different types of people
and we can have a conversation
that all you know, all three of
us. I enjoy that.
A lot of times I feel like I
just I just see this and feel
this huge disconnect
between like our age and older
generations.
And it's like yeah,
very much so.
But but I think a lot of what
it is is we're like
so think about hearing as a
parent think about hearing words
like childhood trauma.
They instantly take that on
themselves like oh, I was a
terrible parent or whatever.
I have a little trouble with my
own mother because we're so
like because I'm in the I'm
cuckoo. I'm in the cocoon a
little bit now. I'm through my
hero's journey. I'm not in the
middle of my hero's journey.
I'm still I said, you know, my
throat still closes up when I
talk, but I'm still trying to
deal with a lot of these things
out. Nothing's wrong with that
either. No, no, yeah.
But but I yeah, thank you for
saying that. I think that
talking about it and getting it
like I am in the middle of it.
I'm not claiming to not be on
the other side of things, but
I'm not ignoring it.
That's for sure.
But I think a lot of the
disconnect is so much of
like.
A lot of it's almost like older
people take it as offensive.
Like we're saying, oh, you were
terrible parents and you didn't.
It's like, no, that's that's not
what what's happening.
Like when we when we say words
like childhood trauma or like
this thing happened to you when
you are a younger thing and now
you have to have this adult
relationship with your parents and
your kid still has childhood
trauma. Absolutely.
But you know what I've learned
is parents do the best with
what they have.
And I bet you their parents
weren't any better.
Right. At least from my
family, I see my I live with my
grandma, my mom, I live on the
second parcel and I see
it like the trauma
and my grandma is just so alive
like she would die without it.
If you like healed her trauma,
she would die. She would send
because that's her.
She needs it to live.
Like she always talks about how
poor she was and all this.
And like it is
her. She cannot move forward in
depression is living in the past
anxiety living in the future.
She doesn't have anxiety.
She has she has some anxiety,
but it's so like trauma.
Like these people back in my day,
like they need it, but us,
it's like I don't it's a part of
me and I appreciate it because
it's brought me here, but I want
to like move forward.
Yeah. And like I know some of my
whole identity. Yeah.
But I have those older generation.
It is a lot of them
and like to tell them to heal
like who are like no.
Right. Like, you know, they
didn't go to counseling.
They didn't have the tools that
we do now. They didn't have
the internet like they weren't
meditating like they weren't
thinking about it in a healthy
way. Right.
Like we are really pushed to do
that. I feel like our generation
is pushed to do that.
I mean, especially like, you
know, people like I imagine I
spent a crazy amount of time
on YouTube and learning about
these things. I don't do you
spend a good amount of time.
Yeah. Yeah. I mean, it's
but but what it is is, you
know, I'm not watching, you
know, Parks and Rec for the
fifth time on YouTube.
I'm which I would love to
but I, you know, I'm like
learning these things like our
Paris just simply or older
people simply didn't have
access to these things.
I mean, so if I wanted to go,
OK, what is, what is
meditation? What is Buddhism?
What is any of these things?
If I wanted to know this
information 30 years ago, I
would have to travel to India,
talk to the right person,
travel, travel. Yeah, I could
find the shaman.
It's six months in India and
then eight months here serving
here. Yeah.
All these things. But nowadays
all of those people 30 years
ago who were doing that like
people who I listened to
every day, they come back
now and they have
conversations about what
they learned and so people
like you and I get to
listen to that information.
So instead of so not that I'm
saying like where I have the
knowledge of a monk travel to
the top of the mountains.
But there is there, you know,
we have some things that are
helpful for people to learn.
And yeah, when you our
knowledge, the internet has made
it to where we know
so much.
The sentence we know more than
our parents doesn't.
That just doesn't make sense.
That's not what I'm trying to
say. Right. But you're more
aware. Yeah, our knowledge
base and the details of
like, you know, further
towards truth and further
towards not ignoring
our feelings, our inner spirit,
not ignoring that stuff.
We're we're figuring that out
and we're able we're getting
slower slowly.
We're starting to put things
into words more and more.
I mean, I feel like a lot of
people listening, you're
probably told at a young age
to shut up or don't say
that, be quiet and public.
You know, don't talk about
that and that blocks
your throw and that blocks
your creativity and like
little kids are just open
imagination like, you know,
they're so excited.
Like to me, telling a kid to
shut up, I know it's like,
I'm not a parent, so I can't
do it. But it like
and every time you're telling
him to shut up, it's like
and then they just get in
this box where they don't
talk or they don't talk
about anything meaningful
and they don't look and they
don't talk from within.
They talk from without, if
that makes sense.
No, it does. So I actually
when I was like nine, my
life started getting just like
super hectic and it was
essentially this what I felt
was anything you have
to say is adding to the
problematic situation that is
your life.
So it was very like it was
very suppressed, what I really
would want to say.
And then so it's kind of, you
know, you get older and you
don't realize that you have
suppressed these sort of
things and a lot of like our
personality traits are like
trying to fit in with
different situations when
we're just when the real
less. It's a way to survive
trauma as a child.
Yeah.
And like the way I was like
thinking today, I was like,
how did I survive my trauma
being overly kind and nice?
Because no one questions the
kind person.
No one thinks that their mom
is using meth in the bathroom.
Right.
No one thinks that this kind
little girl has a fucked up
life at home.
Right.
You know what I mean?
I had some teachers be like,
well, you go OK, but like
no one questions the kids who
are acting out defense tactic.
Right. But just being so
kind to kill them with
kindness.
And I always talk about them.
So no one's asking me about Jay.
No one's asking about Jordan L.
It's always them talking to me.
So I don't have that opportunity
or I don't allow people to ask
me how I'm doing because I was
doing horrible.
Right. Right.
So I was always opening to
listening to my friends.
And I was never really
talking about me until
recently.
But like I was always about
them or other people.
And that was just a defense
mechanism because I wasn't doing
good.
Do you know what I mean?
I had a lot of trauma.
I was angry inside.
Like if you saw me at my house,
way different from like how you
saw me at school.
Yeah. Because if you talk about
it, that means you got to face
it is the thing.
Yeah.
So it's or embarrassed or like
you don't want to like, you
know, it's her.
You don't want to talk about
your her what hurt you.
And do you ever feel sometimes
I feel like we share amongst
our individual friend groups
growing up like, oh, you
know, inevitably we're the
person who people text like,
hey, I've got this thing
going on.
And I love it.
Like it's what I live for.
I love helping people.
And you know, responding with
like, they trust my opinion.
Like I can be straight up with
my friends and they want to hear
it, you know, do you ever
we were talking about before
this about like taking
a lot of that, taking it on,
but not not exactly like
draining it.
Right.
And so you want to go on
a little bit.
What are some ways that you
drain these things?
Like not that like your friends
give you problems and you
got to just like get them away.
But there is a lot of like we
accidentally hold on to things
that aren't ours.
And there's a lot of me personally.
You talk about nature.
I'm huge into nature as well
for this reason.
Forest bathing is real.
Yeah.
It's a force bathing.
Yeah, I want to become like a
forest bathing practitioner.
That's like an epic term.
OK, OK, Jay, tell me about it.
So it's crazy because like I'm
Japanese, right?
So forest bathing is like a
Japanese technique.
And what they're doing with
these depressed patients is
they're just going out with
them in the forest and they're
literally doing brain scans.
And they're carrying depression
and anxiety with the forest.
Fantastic.
So the reason we love and
that's a big part of my Instagram
too is like get outside.
Like you guys are sad.
Go outside and connect
because we're disconnected
because you know what we do?
We wake up in a box.
We get put our food in a box.
We get in a box and we drive
to a box.
We leave the box, get in the
box, go back to the box.
If anybody threatens our box,
we attack it.
We attack their box and you
stay in this box and you're
cyclical human beings and
you're in the box and you're
in the box and you're in the
box and it's like, oh yeah,
hiking like, oh,
it's a fad.
No, it's not.
It's more to me than hiking.
Right.
It's get outside
because nature is just
waiting to heal you.
Yeah.
It is just waiting.
Like I'm getting chills
talking about it because
that's why I'm here is to like
nature is like,
it's perfect.
Right.
You don't even have to do
anything and it's just growing.
You didn't plant that tree.
Who planted that tree?
No one knows.
Isn't it just fascinating?
See, I love doing that.
So because I'm a, you know,
sometimes it's great to turn
off my thinking brain,
but sometimes I like going into
nature and just letting it
rip as in like, oh my God,
like how old could that tree
possibly, oh my God,
how did this lake get here?
Just letting yourself be this
like wondrous explore
of the situation in front of you.
You are the tree.
That's like my meditation is
you are that it is in you.
So what I do is I'll go
outside, barefoot,
I collect things and I just sit
and I usually do this alone
and I sit and
all around you is in you.
You are everything.
And when you can be like that
and sit because it's the God
particle, right?
So if you look at everything
at a molecular level,
it's the same little Buddha guy.
The God, it's called the God
particle.
So that's where I'm like,
God is everywhere.
It's not God up in the clouds
with his beard and the but no
thing against Bible or anything.
But to me, God is everywhere.
I see God everywhere I look
because someone like nature
is like how I connect.
Like I'm like telling Dane,
I'm like my religion
is nature.
Like if we went out and like
worshiped like the trees and
stuff, the world, but just
and just be more like this.
So everything around you
in your house is made from
nature.
Like, do you not see that?
Like your wood table is a tree.
Like everything around you
is created from nature.
The elements.
Yeah.
And I think we just get
can like lose connection.
And I think a lot of depression
is the lack that lack of
feeling connected.
But if you just go outside
and like, you don't have
to do anything.
You know, you don't have to get
somewhere like a lot of people
want to hike to the top.
And I love that too.
But I go to the same spot a lot.
And I just sit and I look at
for something new.
I'm not even looking.
I'm just seeing something new.
Yes, yes.
Because the universe is showing
me new things because I'm
taking the time from my soul.
And when you spend time
with your soul, you learn
more and more and more and more.
But the more I learn, the more
I realize that I am nature.
Like I am you.
Do you know what I mean?
Yeah.
Do you think?
Probably deep but sorry.
No, that's wonderfully deep.
I love it. Keep going deeper.
It's great.
Sometimes I feel that my
so me, for example,
you know, I categorize myself
with ADHD a lot.
And I do that, though.
I'm always very weary of like,
I don't like categorizing myself
because like I don't want to feel
like I'm a victim of it or like
I'm I'm penciling myself in
and my ego struggle.
Yeah, right.
Ego likes labels.
It definitely does.
But I find that
something that I didn't realize
that I wasn't ever being able
to turn off before
I started going into outside
by myself more again the last
couple of years, I like this
task, this task mind where
it's like you need to do something
at all times.
You're always assigning yourself
a task and completing it.
And if you're not in the middle
of it, you actually have this panic.
You're like, I don't have a task
right now. I'm going to grab my
phone. I'm going to do something.
I'm going to take a picture.
I'm going to whatever.
But like when you're outside,
if you give yourself a few hours
and you realize like, I don't have
to have it, the task doesn't
have to be the end.
It could be this in between
like me.
I really would I have
what I have success with is while
I'm outside, getting
myself away from my current thoughts
and my current spot in life is I
think about my life.
Zoom out, zoom way out.
Like when I'm on my deathbed
versus when I was born,
what do I want to be?
Like if I'm looking at my life as
a timeline, like the little pings
are right now.
Like what do I want to like?
OK, I went hiking.
Like I experienced hiking
for this many hours, like, you
know, see it as something
before I die.
I want to have experienced this.
You know, I want to feel the
outdoors.
So like when you say timeline,
so time isn't linear for those
of you listening.
The past and the future are
happening right now.
I think of time as a record
player.
So it's
crazy. So like when talking back
about changing your perception
on your childhood memories, you
change your future.
And they're saying so many times
you can meditate and you heal
and you start to forget memories
that you held onto.
And I feel like memories are
almost keys.
But like I'll forget things so
easily because I don't need to
remember it anymore.
It's not who I am.
Does that make sense?
But when you're talking about
this timeline and these pings,
so your future is happening
right now.
Like everything.
I totally OK.
So it's not a linear.
It's it's totally all right now.
Like the world creating beginning
like dinosaur.
Like it's all here happening
right now.
And that is so important to
realize that you can change
right now.
Like your thought one thought can
change your whole future.
One interaction.
I met my partner and I knew right
away and I went for it.
What if I wasn't there that night?
You know, so it's like but
everything led you up to right
here right now in this moment.
But it's all happening right now.
If that makes sense.
Think of time like and I know
it's super crazy.
But it's like it does.
That's profound though.
That's that's how I see it.
I don't I like was meditating
one day and I was like
because we get so stuck with
right. At least I'm always in
the future.
That's something I need to work
on.
But like I'm like but
like when you're envisioning
yourself and when you're feeling
psychic I almost feel like I'm
tapping in to the future
and I'm getting like a glimpse
of it.
It's not like I'm even like
visioning or manifesting.
It's almost like like I'm like
dipping into the future.
You saw a little bit of like
someone someone showed you a
little bit like it's like a
flat like yeah.
So it's like now the universe
grants me with a vision of me
owning an herbal shop.
Now what that's what I want
to do and what can I do to get
there.
So when you see these memories
or visions of your future
go for it because it's showing
you it for a reason like
my mom always says I had a dream
I was like on a podium and I'm
like you wouldn't have a dream
if you couldn't do it or you
wouldn't have that dream in
the first place.
If that makes sense right.
Yeah yeah yeah like you want
to do this.
I want to do that.
It's all are intuitive.
It's our soul guidance.
You can't win the lottery if
you don't buy a lottery.
Take it right hundred percent
but like this disconnects
so when I get sad it's
because I'm not aligned with my
soul's higher purpose.
And a lot of people I don't know
what I want to do.
But in my big
what spirit tells me is do it
brings you joy.
For me being in my garden
planting plants.
Yeah joy.
That's it.
You're doing it.
You don't have to like do all
these crazy things.
Of course you can but like
joy can't like joys it.
That's all you need.
Right.
It's so simple.
We over complicate it.
You go to these foreign
countries that have nothing in
our eyes.
They're happy.
I know we have more that we
add more.
So we add more problems.
Yeah.
You need to you need to
simplify.
Well me living in my tiny house
I have not been like more happy.
I don't have walls.
I don't have power.
I don't have water.
I don't have a toilet.
OK.
Let's talk about your tiny
house because it's so sick to
me.
I saw a couple of things.
You had a couple of videos
and then we were talking about
you're telling me like a
little bit of the size.
Yeah.
I was like wondering I don't
know.
I don't think that I'm the type
of person who can do it at
this point.
I don't think I don't know.
But it's not for everyone.
Yeah.
But it's so cool that it's
that it's for you and I want
to hear about it.
So tell me about another
person in there.
Oh yeah too.
OK.
So from conceptualization
when you first had the
thought or saw like a tiny
house start there.
This is so I don't know
like how long but I've
always loved like yurts
and little hobbit houses
and like you know it just
feels cozy to me like it's
crazy how you have the
smallest.
So I'm a tourist so I love
home and I love making people
feel comfortable.
Sometimes I feel like when
you're in a big space it's
almost harder to do that.
But you're wrangling
all the way in.
So my house is 24 by 20
and I envision like having
tea parties and like get
together and people are just
so comfortable with themselves
because like when you're in
a small space like you have
to just be.
This is it.
This is the room.
Like you can't like walk away
of the conversation party
and like I'm always in the
kitchen talking to random
people because I can't be
in like the main area.
But when you're like forced
to be in one room together
you really just have to show up.
Absolutely.
And like with my tiny house
like I don't even use all of it
and it's tiny.
So it's like crazy how like
even I have a small space
I'm still not using
all of the space.
Right.
So it's 24 by 20.
Randomly like it's crazy
how it all just like aligned
my lease was up
and my apartment
and my mom just bought a
house and it had a second
parcel and she wanted to
build a house there
and I'm like I don't want to
spend like 1500 on rent.
Like that's just I don't really
want to afford it.
Like I just it's not me.
Like I just I don't know.
I don't like the idea of like
renting to never own
kind of felt like I was like
throwing my money away.
Well you have different
future plans than a lot of
people like you need to buy
a house right now.
It's like what I don't want to
own a house.
Never me.
So my house was $6,000
total and my mom bought it
for me and I'm paying rent.
But it is just like
again I don't have walls
or water or but I live on
my mom has her main house
so I go up there to use
like the kitchen.
We will have that.
We're just like working on
getting electricity.
But it's so comfortable.
It's so cozy and like
it's me my boyfriend and our
two cats and like the cats
love it and our beds up top.
I love sleeping up top.
Oh yeah.
And like it's like a loft like
a yeah like you can't like
stand up up there.
But like you could like sit
up in bed and read.
I can't my partner can't.
But like it's just
and then there's a loft
on the other side for like
we're going to do like a
little meditation like room
because it's like completely
black.
So would you like pillow or
do you like pillows and like
posters and like black it out
because like I like to meditate
in the black.
Perfect.
And like that's like there's
not a lot of places you can
just get like blackness.
Yeah.
But like dark all the time.
So like I'll wake up and I'll
eventually go over there and
I'll just be like dark and I
can meditate.
And then I envision
myself having like an herbal
business like ran out of it
and like I have a garden
already and just people can
come and like I want like a
you pick flower place and I
just want to like bring a
little like I don't know
just energy to the town and
like neighborhood and just have
people come connect
right.
You know with like nature in
like a different way.
I think that's great.
And I think that it'll
definitely shine through like
people.
I could totally envision that
people meeting you and like
just come to my tiny house
like it would be such a great
full on experience.
You know we forget a lot of
times when we're when we're
eating dinner you know
where we're like oh this is
so good but like we forget
about the process of going
to the store.
We forgot the process of
cutting it and washing it and
all these things and when you
can add like they get to see
like your cheerful face and you
tell them a little bit about
what they're what they're taking
home or yeah not
just eating wise but that's
great.
Yeah I think adding to the
experience of them coming up
to your house will see like I
want to do like you pick
herbal place so you're
really connected to your
medicine.
It's not like oh I'm buying
like St. John's work for my
depression.
It's like no you're picking
it and you're dry and I'll
dry it for you and you can
go home with it or making
teas for yourself.
And so what I envision
is like we're very intuitive
and we're very like you see
something in your body like oh
I want that I don't even know
what that herb is but I'm
attracted to it.
Well you probably need it but
we don't ever get to see our
medicine like that so I feel
like we can't heal ourselves
because we aren't ever given
the opportunity to look at
our medicine in the face.
So that's why I want to do
like a you pick herbal
place and you pick garden
so where it's like just
walk in the garden with you
and meditate and just talk
and pick out three herbs that
you're drawn to.
I'm not going to tell you
what they are you know you
just I will if you ask but
like you just see what you're
drawn to and then you pick it
and you need that because who
picked that right.
I like that.
So it's like there's not a lot
of I haven't found a place
that's like there's one place
in Portland that's kind of
like that but I just wanted to
like a more on a small scale
right but it's connect people
to the whole world to make
this big corporation or
anything. A lot of times
people think that growth is
the only I'm a growth
mindset person but sometimes
like giant growth isn't
always what we're going for
like your goal here is
to make it to where people
can come here and and and pick
with their intuition and you
could help them with that.
Like that sounds like a great
goal.
Yeah. And I mean I do want
like a wellness center.
That's something that I've
envisioned for 10 years.
I've drawn it up.
I've seen it but that is
like a 20 year plan 30 year
plan. That's not something
but it's my main driving
force to everything I do is
to create this wellness center
for people to really come
and heal like heal the soul.
OK. So yeah heal the soul.
That's what you mean to say
wellness center.
What are you because you're
let's expand a little bit more
about you who you are.
I feel like because I that's
like who you are.
You're you're a healer.
Yeah. Yeah.
Like what are right.
I mean it seems seems like it
right.
What do you what do you feel
as like you're like if it's
like OK I have a duty a calling
like here's what here's how
I help people like what
wellness center.
Yeah.
It's like something I I see
it I feel it I act
as if it's already here.
You know because I see it so
vividly.
It's just it is what it is
like commune like living together
something that I crave.
I'm Native American like I crave
missing like living side by side
with people and like sharing
and bartering and like growing
our own like what I envision
like I won't have a I don't
know if I want kids but I
when I do see my child it's
at this wellness center like
living like this lifestyle
because that's the kind of life
I want to create for the future
is like you don't have to live
here but like a place to come
and just be you don't have to
know who you are your ego
or whatever like let's grow
vegetables together like and
pick your food and let's
prepare it together and eat
like family style and like
really be connected to the earth
and like let's meditate together
and like just live in harmony
with the earth.
Have you know.
I love that I I I kind of
think about like a meditation
retreat center I like here
I think so I work with
musicians and artists and stuff
and so for example I had a
videographer homie over two
nights ago and we were talking
about like he was just saying
like I get so caught up with
these things we're just
talking about like I I have
so many friends I hang out
with all of them and like a
love hanging out with them
but I have this trip and it
seems like there's no time to
like you just always have a
plan and you're doing doing
doing and we were talking
about and I have plans
with some other musicians of
doing like a writing retreat
here where it's just like three
days where it's just like you
know leave your phone upstairs
if you can or you know maybe
don't have to but and just
connect to like the structure
of of not like working
working working but like just
like we're going to write
if it comes out but yeah like
sit in the backyard in a hammock
and write like not we need
to start a timer and like get
this done in an hour like
you know they explore what
just give me like anxiety I
know right yeah not writing
from the soul it's like ego
like oh yes like I'm forcing
myself yeah do you write a
lot do you yeah okay I know
that you write your captions
on Instagram are great you
right there do you write pen
and paper too yeah and it's
crazy because I don't read
what I write ever I do that
to you I do that too and like I
probably won't listen this
podcast you know not not like
myself I listen to your podcast
but like this like how dare
you what who's the guy in
the office the main guy Steve
Krill he never watches his
TV shows the only time he's
seen them or as if his kids
are watching him but I feel
that I don't know why I don't
it's it's almost like it's not
me but it is me but it's like
you know it and I'll over
analyze it or like oh I said
that or why did they say that
or I like pick at it you know
like a control freak I get
that you know okay so because
that's come up a lot like
doing this podcast because I'm
friends with most of the
people or besides a few of
them so far I've been prior
friends with them and so
that's an open contact and
they're like oh I hate my
voice or like please don't
send this or make my voice
out but it's a but people
like love my voice that's the
thing it's like I hate it I
think I sound like a little
kid and it's like too high
pitch and everyone's like my
part is like I love your voice
it's sweet he's like I can
hear you from a while away
like but we're all that's
here but we're all in our own
head cavities thinking that it
sounds so strange but it's a
lot of the times Alan Watts
he says this he says this
thing that always sticks with
me we somehow an event is
ruined if we don't get a
good picture of it you know and
sometimes it's like we do feel
the need to you know I find
this I'll take a snapchat and
then I'll rewatch it before I
post it those sort of things
if I do that we always think
like okay can I rewind time and
make that better or whatever
and it's you never can as
much as we think we want to
I feel that but it's it's you
just are who you are in this
moment and you're always
improving I guess you don't
really care to like I mean I
do like sometimes when I'm
writing it's sometimes I get
overwhelmed with all the thoughts
that I have right and I just
get consumed and then sometimes
I get like well I'm not here
yet right so sometimes when I
read all my goals or things
that I want to do I read like
my goals all the time and
like I'm an advocate like law
of affirmation and planners
and mantras and like I am
enough I am enough I am enough
I am I will write the same
thing hundred like crazy like
well it's like no like
because like you need you
need to tell yourself you
need to be reminded like I'll
write on my mirrors like
I usually don't like to look
in the mirror but it's like no
I need to show up for myself
and look at myself and realize
that I am enough and everyone
that's listening is enough
and I don't think that we
tell each other that enough
I tell my partner every day
you are enough I love you for
you and we don't I just
got chills saying that to
myself like we don't tell
ourselves like our part like
the real things you know oh
yeah I love you oh I love
you love we say it like a
word you have to say but
like look your partner in the
eyes and like mean it and
tell them because you don't
know what they're going
through right I mean we've
talked about that like
you're with somebody and you
don't even know what they're
feeling how often do you
think that happens we just
hide it because we're ashamed
of our feelings and it's like
no like talk about it I'm
advocate for talking about
my feelings I probably talk
about them too much but I
have so many that I'm like
let's talk about I need to
dissect it yeah you don't
understand it I mean yeah
you're trying to understand
what's what's coming out
and you're trying to allow
other people to understand it
to yeah a lot of times we
keep things inside and you
know with writing I don't
even know what I think
sometimes until I'm writing
and I'm like oh that's what
I think yeah that makes sense
I don't know same you know
I feel that put your words
give your give yourself a
place to put the word so they
start to to come together
like the past three days
I've actually had like a
little bit of a block
which I never usually get
like you know the writer's
block or whatever I'm like
what's happening
and I think it's just
happening because sometimes
like I get so much I'm
like hyper spinning that I
think sometimes I just need
to like chill and not
always be with like spirit
and divine and like
sometimes I just need to be
human and just be present
because I'm chronically
hearing like things
not like bad things
but like act on this
here's this great idea
you need to do this
here's this follow this into
funnel funnel funnel funnel
or like oh my gosh
like really look at the
but sometimes I just need
to be like shut off
so I can just like reset
and recharge right
because we're batteries
if you think about it
if you're draining it
and you're putting it
out there and you're putting
out there and something I
also started thinking about
was how many people
are like seeing me
and how much energy
and what kind of energy
is going on to people
like when they're seeing
my stuff
and my because I'm triggering
people
I can feel that
I can feel I'm triggering
people and that energy
even though we're not
physically with them
it's attached
do you know what I mean
and I'm here to trigger
people
because I'm waking people up
expand on the word
triggering because I think
that political
political stuff has ruined
the words like triggering
I'm not political but yeah
I know but
but it's I feel like
when I hear that
I hear that
I hear that in the news
okay so sometimes
for example
I'm pretty happy
that makes someone
upset
because they're not happy
okay
or I'm honest
and that makes someone
unhappy
because they're maybe
not being honest
with themselves
I'm being authentic
I'm not wearing makeup
that triggers some girls
because they aren't
doing that
and they're mad at
themselves
you know what I mean
so who does she think
she or the like
you know I've had people
like upset at me
for being nice
I've had so many women
not like me
because of how
genuinely nice I am
it's because they don't
feel free to do that
because they have to have
this guard up
I don't have a guard up
I'm very open
yeah definitely
I think that so many people
are so
unaware of their own guards
their own masks
their own armor
that they're
like pushing up against
themselves
yeah well I realize
I'm like I don't think
people you know like
sometimes people are
doing something that
bothers you
I'm like
but they're not
trying to bother you
like you are just being
bothered by it
but that's probably not
their intention
like someone cut you off
that's gonna keep happening
until it doesn't bother you
people coming off
I'm like
who even taught us that term
like maybe they're busy
maybe their dad just died
maybe they're going to
appointment
like you do not know
what people are going through
I've got people off on
accident
oh yeah okay
you know what I mean
driving is a great way
to test your triggers
right
oh driving is a great way
if you think that you're
like totally in control
of your emotions
but you still get road rage
that's something
where I'm like
oh I'm cool
com collected guy
like whatever
I can keep my shit to myself
then I would notice
I would get road rage
or somebody would be
going 68
in the fast lane
on the freeway
and I'm like
I'm gonna ride their ass
because
so they know that
I'm telling them
because I'm God
right
yeah
gosh we do these
fullest things
so I
this is the cool story
that popped them ahead
as you were talking about this
I'm talking about
like following intuition
right
so
you know think about
let's say
words like manifest
words like
I'll just tell the story
so essentially
I was
out loud
I knew that I was working
on my road rage
and I was actually
so I was driving back home
and I was
in Lexington
coming back
I was gonna take the background
here to Castle Rock
and
I was behind this old person
who was going
dangerously
it's just 25
and a 45
and I rode there
but like
just what I've been thinking
about it
and then I started to get
annoyed
and I was like
you know what
I'm not in a rush right now
I don't
I don't need
I'm not dying to get home
what am I doing at home
I'm gonna
listen to the same podcast
I'm listening to right now
like
so I
right
hung a left
I was like
let's just
let's go the long way
even if I'm behind him
I'm gonna be a couple minutes
behind him
that's fine
I won't even catch up
so I went the long way
right
and I'm going through
and I didn't realize
that I was driving past
someone
essentially it was a
distant family member
on Shaly's side
of the family
was standing in her front yard
I was like
I forgot you lived here
oh okay universe
she's standing in her front yard
looking at her front yard
after she just mowed the lawn
and she's just going through
a recent divorce
she was literally just like
I hope I'm doing this right
I talked to her for a few minutes
he stopped
and we had this conversation
and I was driving away
and she texted me
this long thing like
hey like thanks for
like I
I needed that little
conversation sort of thing
and it was just this
so that's why I was trying to
I was trying to connect the words
like manifest words like
intuition
like
follow the good in your heart
in your soul
like when you
like so me
I was trying to take care of myself
not because
I'm
I was trying to change my perspective
of I don't want to be
road rage guy
I don't want to be angry
what
this guy driving slow
should not affect me
that's my problem
and I should figure it out
so me following
and wanting to heal that
led to me healing someone
helping someone a little bit
in
yeah it's so important
right
so and I think that
a huge thing that
well life starts
opening these doors
the universe did that
for you
absolutely
that guy was put there for you
what if he wasn't even there
like it's I was saying
this is in my head
like
but that happened for you
a lot of people
why is this happening to me
to me versus change that to for me
love that
why is this happening for me
I've been in like a car accident
and I was the best day of my life
I literally almost died
yeah it was the best day of my life
I had an out of body experience
it was the most spiritual day of my life
I felt so blessed
I should have flipped but I didn't
it was like
but you know what I mean like
you need to change your perspective
on your life
you can change those words
you know if you grew up in a
negative home it's harder
but
you can change it
especially if you're with negative people
your partner is negative
or like your friends are negative
and
unfortunately sometimes
if they're not willing to change
like you
I use this term
you got to rise up
for yourself
like it yeah
it's really hard
it is
but you have to do it for you
yeah
because no one's going to do it
for you but you
it's it's so important to like
take that stand
and be like you know like
you don't have to stay with the
same friends
if they're not
if they're not matching up with
they're always going to be your friends
yeah
but when you're
when I'm seeing my friends do things
that I don't want to do
or only talk about other people
you know the small town gossip
blah blah blah
and then and then and then and then and then and then
and then
that just doesn't light me up
and I'm all about lighting my soul up
like light me up spiritually
soulfully
I don't need to have these
this kind of conversation is my daily
with my partner
like I need this
I hate the small talk
it's like
cringe to me
how are you
how are you good good like bye
and then they both
both both parties know that
like we don't really want to be
saying this we're saying
I don't care
I think we have to
and the truth is sometimes
I don't care how you're doing
because sometimes I just am not that
mindset where I don't care
and it's not it's not a bad thing
to not care all the people
you don't know them
why do you care
you can't be walking
if you walk around the town
and you see 1700 people
you can't take the stress of
I need to know how every single
1700 of these people are
you know 100%
it's not my job
yeah
because what happens to me
is if I engage people read it wrong
people think I'm hitting on them
or people like
all right
you know
and it's like just because I'm asking
if you like your job
it doesn't mean that I'm like hitting on you
but people like take nice
and like my boyfriend always says
like people take your nicest for granted
and it's
but I'm not going to stop being me
but I've had these conversations
at my coffee shop
where people break down in tears
because they're telling me
things they've never talked about
so sometimes you do have that ability
no matter where you're working
when you
if you get that urge in the grocery store
to hey go talk to someone
go do it
definitely
yeah I love that
do you know what I mean
do you ever get that
and you see someone
and you're like
I want to go talk to them
no that's weird
every time I go and talk to them
that person is so thankful
well in being open to
who they are
fully like
like giving them a little bit of room
to you know
love to be heard
yeah definitely
and I think that a time
going back to we were talking about
like a lot of older people feel a little disconnected
I think in ways a lot of
you know
just listening to
someone who needs
someone to talk to right now
I always think about
think about nowadays
you're cooking
some something
like you and your partner
are cooking something
back in the day
you would text your mom
or call your mom
or ask your mom
like hey what's
what's the ingredient for this
and grandma taught her
and whatever
but nowadays you
mom doesn't exist in that
you just look to Google
Google has the answer
for that recipe
or how long you cook it
and I just think of all these
technology has changed
a lot of different areas
of our life
not just like cooking
and getting recipes
where we've cut out
a lot of our
communication
older people
and just other people
so I feel like
we're connected through the internet
but we are very disconnected
and sometimes we're reminded
in situations like this
where you're like
follow your intuition
talk to that person
if you think you need to
and I feel like some people
like do not know
how to communicate
I actually think
a lot of the population
cannot have a genuine conversation
because they
they aren't authentic
with themselves
so how can they be authentic
with me
and I see that a lot
I can tell so much
by someone
by what they talk about
to me in the first
few seconds
so there's this technique where
you ask someone
how they're doing
and they talk
and you wait one
two
three
before you respond
and then they'll talk again
and you wait
one
two
before you respond
because people hate silence
right
oh right
so it's like
if you don't talk
they'll fill the void
and it's always interesting
to see what people have to say
because you can learn
so much from someone
by just listening
yes
I usually like to be the
I used to grow up
like talk
like talk talk talk
because I made HD whatever
but like
my recent years
I like to listen
because I'm learning more
when I'm listening
you know what I mean
and also I'm like
coming into these crazy
conversations
with these crazy random people
but it's like
wow my life manifested
some amazing conversations
with crazy people
and we each have something
to teach
which is like this podcast
yeah that's what it is
doesn't matter who it is
like someone at the gas station
like
don't be like
oh they have nothing to teach
me
everyone has something to teach
you because you've all
had different life experiences
and I also believe
we're all messengers
nothing's random
sometimes you hear
like a random statement
and you take it for granted
but everything
you are hearing in your life
you are meant to hear
even if it's on the radio
even if it's on
I don't listen to commercials
or ads
because it's like
subliminal messaging
but if you hear something
on the radio
like
and it resonates with you
and it triggers this emotion
or something like
the universe is a frequency
and you're tuning in
so like everything
you're hearing
and you're supposed to hear
yeah but I feel like
so many people
because I always wonder
like okay what
what's the difference
like let's say now
versus before
for me
just using me as an example again
like if there was these messages
these like
man follow this
like here's
here's what you need to go through
right now
like a lot of times it's hard to
to see it like that
usually I don't see it
like that till later
right yeah but
but do you think just by being
like
honestly it seems like
just by being open
and like so if someone approaches you
you're in a bad mood
someone approaches you
instead of being like
I'm in a bad mood
I don't like
let's get this conversation over with
because I don't
talk to this person
because I'm feeling this
well they can feel that
yeah but if you
but what about if you instead
stay open to
this person
well think about the story you
told me about earlier
right
oh oh oh on Halloween
yeah
we can talk about that
yeah it's up to
if you're personal stuff
certainly
so I'll retell it
so something that I felt the need
to tell Jay when she got here
two years ago
and I think I've mentioned this
night on the podcast
somewhere at some point
oh wow
maybe episode 14
I don't think that I mentioned you
in it but
I essentially
two nights before a big Halloween
show
we were renting out this place
and I was throwing a big event
and I did the decor
and I DJed all night
and the graphics
and I like I like trying to take
care of all of it
like the event side of things
I like doing the whole big thing
but two days before this
my hard drive crashed
which means that I had to
scramble to get all my music
and try to find it
and I'm like waiting
on different loading screens
and I don't know where half
my songs are
and some of them got delayed
it's all this
it was two days of
not a lot of sleep
if any
and a lot of stress
and then I had to leave for
an away show
the next morning
essentially
I was very stressed
was going through it
and Jay came up
and because we've been like
friends in different ways
like we're always happy
to see each other
always been friends
in different ways
but not super close
well she came up and
while you're DJing
while I was DJing
while I was yeah
like while I was up there
which is not me
I usually don't do that
I mean I like to be up on the stage
but not like that
right
no but it
so what I
the reason why I felt compelled
to tell you was
because like it was kind of weird
but it was
thoroughly finished
what was I doing
so you came up and you
not like right away
like you just came
to start rubbing my back
but you came up
and you were saying
nice things to me
you're like
you're doing great
like you were
essentially
you were encouraging me
but I was inside
what was happening
was I was very stressed
I was having a
five six hour long panic attack
and to wind things down
probably negative
and maybe your mind
I was very negative
I was very
my suicidal thoughts
were just
just like that night
was
was very a
suicidal contemplation night
so heavy
yeah and so
but
but what I had told you
when you when you got here
that story is
is I remember
you coming up
and trying to help me
and I was so focused
on my own thing
I didn't realize
what was going on
it was like this like
I know who you are
but you're bugging me
sort of thing
and I remember
I snapped at you
I was like you need to get off stage
like please leave me alone
and I remember
the reason why I remember it
is because
that moment
your reaction to it
made me realize
what I said
what I was doing
like I don't want to snap at people
like I'm being aggressive
I'm being mean
I don't
what am I doing
so
because you were instantly
like you
you were like
okay
I get it
I understand
I'm probably I'm so
like you walked away
like sad
and it just stuck with me
because I was like
that's how
like I was feeling this thing
and me saying
one sentence
wasn't up to just
shove it right into today
it's like
how I reacted
is how you are
reflection of how you're feeling inside
because I'm an empath
so I'm trying to give you all this love
because empath to empath
and I
and I could feel
I was very drunk that night
but I could feel
even in your music
that something was different
I could tell your stress
I could feel
I mean
you always play good music
but it was
something it wasn't you
that was way off
and yeah
like it wasn't
like as heartfelt
and like
everything kind of
wasn't working
but you're
it was an inner reflection of you
it wasn't working
because you weren't working inside
right
how I interpreted it
absolutely
and like
me rubbing your back
yeah it's not
like out of context for like
but it's like
it was
and I was like
blacked out at that point
so it's crazy that
I'm doing this
like
as a healer
I'm more like
open to like
touching you
because I was like drunk
but
it was like
I could sense it
so much
and you really needed that
obviously
because it stuck with you
and that's why I want to say that
what you do for people
you might think it's minor
but it plays an impact
the butterfly effect
showing compassion
when
they're not showing compassion
towards themselves
is everything
seriously
yeah like you
you don't know what you're doing
like like the
that that moment
where you
like you made me
snap out of my stuff
I mean
I made me
snap out of my stuff
by me being to you
unfortunately
you have to be the person
my kindness triggered you
yeah
it triggered you
because you were not that way
and you want to be that way
and that's who you are
in the heart
and it
snapped
and this person came out of you
that wasn't really you
but it was you at that time
and you
by me seeing sad
you were able to see
like
an internal reflection of you
on someone else
because we're mirrors
right
exactly
yes
and you're like
whoa
I don't want to be like that
or wow
why was I like that
that's not me
and the world comes rushing in
and you're like what
you know
you look at
you stop these
crazy thoughts
that have been catapulting you
for hours and days
or whatever
and you
you almost become present
with what's going on
well like when I was coming here
like
me being like a lightworker
lightworker is just basically
someone whose mission is to come
raise the frequency of the planet
I've known that for a while
I like walked into a room
in this
one of my psychic teachers
like oh you're a lightworker
like she like can see it
so people can see it in your aura
that's like you know
when you walk into a room
people always look at you
like
because people can feel your energy
I've always felt like
I'm very comfortable to be around
I feel like I'm very
people can be open with me
I've never had
people open up too easily to me
sometimes
but that's why I'm here
on the planet
and once you step into that role
you just like
nothing it surprises me anymore
like nothing
like picking up a piece of trash
you know
instead of being angry at that trash
be thankful the trash is there
to pick up
because you pick it up
and you might inspire someone
else to do the same
exactly exactly
I talk about
Travis Pastrana
motocross guy
back in the day
I remember when I was young
he did the first backflip
and it was like
what?
oh my god
me and my buddies were just freaking out
but then like weeks later
like just weeks
nobody had ever done this
weeks later
multiple people are doing backflips
catalyst
it's in you
it's just you can't see it
sometimes you have to see it
in someone else
but I talk you know
about being empath
and being
everyone is psychic
that's listening
everyone has powers
you just don't realize
that they're powers
because it's you
but you ever like
know something intuitively
that's psychic
like don't think of psychic
as a little chris of the ball
and I gotta go pay
to see the future
right right right right
like everyone has
these gifts
and everyone has a reason
that they're here on the planet
nothing is random
like I always talk about
this is the greatest
biggest shift that the galaxy
has ever seen
and you are here on it
like it's here for a reason
if you're listening to this
you're listening to this
for a reason
right
do you know what I mean
and like it's
nothing is random
I always talk about that
like it's not random
if your life sucks
change your perception
do you know what I mean
I mean I know it's hard
and it's like
because I've been low
like I've been there before
where I like didn't get out of bed
and it's dark
and I'm depressed
and I don't know what I want to do
with my life
and la la la la la la la la la la la la la la
not good enough
but like take that time
to just rest
and it's okay to be like that
and that's the thing
if you are depressed right now
it's okay
because it can get better
right
same with anxiety
like it's okay
like it's gonna be okay
and that's the thing
because people have been through worse
and they're okay
like you can do it
doesn't matter where you're at
like it's gonna be okay
yeah
if you if you follow the thought
instead of just doing your best
to avoid the thought
and distract yourself from the thought
I know it's
you don't always want to get into the ring
with with a thought
and think that you can just strangle it
when you're feeling anxiety
you can be very depressed of course
but when you feel that you can
like all right
why am I feeling like that
like let's see if I can work this out
and I'm in a more emotionally balanced state
yeah
a lot of times if you follow the thought
of of fear
it's it's just
it leads all the way back to like
a simple fear
like I'm a fear
I'm afraid of
so say like you having anxiety
and your heart's just going like
you're like am I gonna die
am I gonna die
and if you just follow these thoughts back
you know
and from a sane position
it's like I'm not
I'm not gonna die
I'm gonna be fine
yeah
it was oh we were talking about
something with an edible too
yeah I took some shrooms
and I took an edible
and my heart was like
like I could feel it like in my toes
and I was like oh my god my anxiety
like I'm gonna die a little bit
but
I knew that's not how I'm gonna go out
I'm not gonna die on my bed
in my tiny house at 24
from shrooms and an edible
like once I just accepted it
I stopped feeling my heart
I just felt oneness
and connection
and I just was
and I can't
when you like
tap into the frequency of the universe
and you just are
it's just like
it's almost like you're breathing
for the first time like
like that's how it felt
like
just
like you just feel like
it just is
like it's so hard to put into words
like it's just it's like ego dissolved
you dissolve
I'm not male
I'm not female
I'm not a nurse
like I'm not this
I'm not that
I don't live in Kelso
like
none of that matters
right
it just
do you see the
I see like
so many like like psilocybin
in MDMA
and like the research they're doing
of course around
like healing depression and
and
it rewires your brain
oh yeah it's
structurally
numbers
listener
if you haven't heard much about this
the numbers are
through the roof like
people like PTSD
like
if there's so many great
yeah micro dosing
loved micro dose
there's a lot of
states and stuff
that are
very quickly making things
Colorado
Oregon's getting on it
like decriminalizing
and
I'm excited for the future
what a
I love to talk about this too
the government
makes it so illegal
because it doesn't want its people
to wake the
fuck up and see how corrupt
the world is
because when you take shrooms
you see it for how it is
there's no veil
and you also begin to love
yourself and the government
doesn't want you to love
yourself because guess what
we are powerful
yeah
they can't
buy us when we're
like powerful beings
and we realize
we are the creators
of our life
they can't control you
anymore
yep
when you're brainwashed
and you're a sheep
which is fine
if you're there
but you have the power
to wake up
and this is like
what the podcast is
it's the wave right now
everyone's waking up
faster numbers
and everyone 2020 hit
people are waking up so fast
I'm like what the fuck
is this energy inside of me
right right right right
why am I just quitting my job
like I don't want to do this
like blah blah blah
and people are like
waking up like
I mean that's what I have
I have multiple people on the
podcast
entrepreneurs business owners
who are more recently
like I do realize
that I wasn't happy
and so I had to do
what made me happy
and here's what I'm doing
and it's great
literally
that's and your
universe supports you
it supports you
because
you have unique gifts
that you came here to do
and if you're not
tapping into that
you're gonna feel dead
for me
and almost anyone
if you don't feel like
you belong here
or you don't feel
like you have a purpose
you're not gonna feel alive
you're gonna feel in that rack
and that's super hard
because it's hard to figure
out what you want to do
but you start with
what makes you happy
exactly
oh that's what I was
totally just gonna say
so like music
my thing with music
I you know through
let's say okay
let's start for me
trauma
in trying to just get away
from the world around me
I was a walk man
disc man guy
like just give me music
I'm putting headphones on
so I can escape
what's going around
I had a lot of time
by myself
a lot of time
like walking places
by myself
so following that
so as I get older
I got
I never picked up
I mean I picked up a guitar
like kind of dingled
around on it
just myself
but I was never in choir
never in music classes
orchestra
any of these things
but I just kept
as life goes on
following it
I'm like oh okay
I get older
and I
I didn't know exactly
what I wanted to do
but the way I was able to quit
my mill job
was finally I was like
okay I gotta like
take this leap
and do school
I was like
I don't know what I want to do
still
I don't
I don't know the answers
but I do love music
yeah
and it feels right
so I started going after it
and then it teaches me
all this audio stuff
and now I'm an audio engineer
now I have this podcast
and just
so essentially
one thing
after another
just following this
my love
and allowing myself to
to say like
you know what you do love music
and that's so okay
and there can be something there
like maybe you haven't discovered it yet
but
but you can search for it
and I think just
we also like
when you make that step of quitting
it's scary
no doubt
like
like it's like the stability right
but
the universe grants you
like the seven fold
like one thing
that you
you leave one bad thing behind
not bad
but like
something you
it's making you miserable
doesn't match up with you
and you
when you cut that off
your DNA like
like rewires
right
and it aligns
and then you start doing
with what you align with
and then it's going to go
bam, bam, bam, bam
and you're going to meet
people who support you
and like
yes, yes, yes, yes
well
the, the, the, the
yeah it's
it's so crazy
well going down
this chair just keeps sliding down
but it's
it's crazy
like at first
I feel like I didn't give it to myself
like I would do the school
and then I just felt like such a fool
and I
I feel like
but that's ego
right
I know that
there was this like falling period
I'm not going to make enough
no one's going to listen
I'm not good enough
no one cares
what am I doing
like what
I need to like
this isn't going to support me
exactly
yeah
who put those thoughts in your head
exactly
that's not soul
that's how you know
soul is love
fear is ego
so if you're getting negative thoughts
you can go
okay
and you don't have to dismiss your ego
but you can say
okay ego I hear you
but where is my soul
and then soul starts pouring in love
most definitely
and you can do love
after I do affirmations every day
I am enough
say that
and let yourself know
I am an herbalist
like I own a wellness center
and you're demanding it
we did
for New Year's
a couple of our friends
and Shay and I
we went down to
we did vision boards
yeah
and I love
you know
and honestly
I'm not kidding
I have it
as we're walking downstairs
we leave our bedroom upstairs
and it's on the wall
I plan on moving it every few weeks
because I don't want to get
get complacent about it
but I honestly stop
in the mornings
and often at night
before I'm going to bed
and I look at it
and I'm like
I know these things are
are
this is what I'm doing
yeah
I don't know the timeline yet
but like these are
doesn't matter
this is what's happening
this is who I am
this is what's
and I think
we talk
my other friends and I
we were talking
more recently a lot about
like a
so church for example
church a Sunday
like a service
we were talking about
the importance of
maybe trying to have
like an every other
every other week
or twice a month
or something
having like a Sunday
get together with our friends
and reconnecting
with these things
like so
kind of how we have
our meditations
that we every morning
like
I am
I'm a good person
I'm a this
I'm an herbalist
I'm a you know
you reaffirm
if you had like a weekly
or bi-weekly thing
even with your friends
where you out wowed
like community
is everything this year
so I like mentioning
on this podcast
because if
if any listeners have
like oh I can do that
with my friends
like please do it
yeah whatever
whatever pops
into your brain
right here
if anything
like if you're like
I have a couple of friends
who probably get together
like
twice a month
let's just
set six months aside
and put it in the calendar
right now
you know
and I
um
it's funny to say
like because I'm hosting
my first full moon circle
you are
what tell me
tell me about this
so Holly
my friend Holly
she's like a astrologer
she's amazing
we've like
wanted to do events
forever
and she just moved
into this apartment
and it has like a space
so we rented the space
and
we're just hosting
like a full moon event
and we're going to be
talking about
like the moon
and how it affects you
and because like
a lot of people don't
know that the moon
affects you
like
right yeah
we see tides
and we're like
that's not connected
like full moon
new moon
there's only a little bit
of water in our body
but we're 70
percent water
the moon in the sky
controls the tides
like
that affects your inner tide
okay
right
so the full moon is in Leo
and it's all about
the sacred solar chakra
which is power
I am enough
and so we're just gonna
it's like
just a place for people
to open up
and just to connect on
to allow
time to just connect
so I feel like
so many people
don't just allow time
to like
connect in a sober place
because I quit drinking
which I told you
so much of my get-togethers
so let's go grab a beer
which is fine
cool fun
but I want to like
tell me your dreams
and visions
and let's talk about it
and how can you get there
yeah
and sometimes a bar
it just doesn't open up
that part of a conversation
you know sometimes it doesn't
I mean it's
Portland bars
you know I like to go to
Portland bar
it's so crafty and creative
but
I'm seeing like
my friends just want to hang out
like I feel like we just have to
like we
need to like create
like I think I need to create a show
and entertain all the time
and like
but it's like
my friends just want to hang out
like get coffee
and hang out
like it doesn't have to be like
let's go with fucked up
and rage
and because like
that's such a big part of my
identity
and like a lot of people that know me
like I was always raging
like since I was little
like I've always been like
party fun dancing like
but you know
when you just
your friend just want to sit
with you and be with you
and just talk
you know a lot of times like hanging
out before you go to the bar
at your house
getting ready together
yeah that's like the best part
yeah it's like
we need more of that
yeah that's super cool that
what's it called
the moon thing one more time
what's it
it's just full moon
it's just a full moon gathering
it's just like
a place to come and learn
and Holly's like again
really into astrology
so she's going to talk about how
this
the astrology of this full moon
and how it affects you
personally and in general
and then we're just going to
kind of talk about
how the full moon affects you
in general
and then we'll do like a little ritual
and each everyone's going to get
like a crystal
which is related to the full moon
and how to use crystals
if you don't know anything about them
you get to take it home
and then
I'll be doing like affirmations
that you can take home
and just
just a place for like people
to come and connect
right
you know what I mean
it's so cool and it's
you know
like the way that I see
like talking about my timeline
like oh take a look at that
it's cool to see like
you know
in five years
whatever the equivalent
of this little event you're doing
like what could that be
like maybe it's going to be this
it's going to be 100 people
maybe there's you know
that's not how they said
but like it's
I know this is like ego or not
but I have dreams
where I'm talking in front of a lot of people
with their hands up
like not like it's like religious
but it's like
I feel like
I meant
I feel like I have this voice
and this wisdom
this internal book
and like what's the point
of keeping it in
right
I feel like it's a disservice
to the universe
to not share like my knowledge
I'm beginning to feel that way
more and more
I'm like I have to
like I'm supposed to
supposed to write this thing
like yeah
and maybe we don't get it
but what I'm realizing is
people are coming up to me
and saying remember
when you said this to me
well I did it
I'm like I don't remember
saying that at all
oh my gosh
totally totally
but I'm
yes
because you are planting the seeds
right
you know you
you're
people might not understand you
when you're saying
or you might not vibe
with this podcast
but you're hearing it
your subconscious is hearing it
and your subconscious
vibes with it
your ego might not vibe with it
but something is hearing it
and it's
your subconscious doesn't forget
right that's what
I notice a lot of
my mother living with me
a lot of this stuff
I hit a lot of instant
like I'll say something
or she'll be
for example this
like she'll be
walking in the kitchen
as I'm listening to something
while I'm cooking
and she'll
it'll like hit her
she'll say something
and she'll say something
like uncomfortable
or like a joke about it
or like make fun of it
or whatever
and I like I let it go
because in a couple days
she'll come back
yeah like she'll almost like
I don't even
I won't even be listening
the same thing
but she'll find a way
to maybe like
bring it up
yeah bring it up
and I'm like oh okay
so you did kind of think
about it like
but at first
you got to realize
you're so right
at first there is
part of us
we're like
why I don't
what the sign
you know
but if you just
stay stay open to it
and a lot of times
it's working in the back
of your mind for you
well if you would have told me
like four years ago
that I wouldn't be drinking
right
yeah right
like that's such a big part
of me
but I just kind of like
with not drinking
like I just realized
that it's not going to get me
personally to where I want to go
and I'm not one of those people
that can just have one
and I know that about myself
so why even go there
my partner's recovered
my mom my dad like
I'm breaking the trauma
like my mom has nine years
clean next month
and it's like
I want to be like that
wonderful
like I want to be like that
like I don't
I don't want a substance
to control me
because alcohol does
like when I
once I start
I want more
and I want it the next day
and the next
even if I'm hungover
like I'm like
oh when can I feel better
to drink again
and it's like this parasite
inside my brain
and it's like craving alcohol
and it's like
what really wants it though
what don't I want to feel
and same with smoking
I'm like
I've been a stoner
for like 10 years
but lately I quit smoking
because I'm
I was numbing it out
marijuana
I mean it's good for my anxiety
yeah it's legal
yeah it helps me sleep but
it was
excuse me it was numbing me out
it was like it was like
yeah it's
it it does
num me out
definitely it does
I mean I
I still smoke quite a bit too
I'm trying to figure out
like what this phase of my life is
but why do we
why
what am I missing
and then I just started to really
and that's why I kind of
quit coffee
because I'm like
I've never been
cleaned from any substance
I've always had a
stimulant
or we I'll
I love to drink coffee
and then smoke a bowl
right
I mean I do too
but that's the thing is
we we don't really stop
and say like
oh like what am I
without these things
that like it like
and that's where I'm at
yeah
and it's hard
so how do you feel like
you've been you've
you've been not drinking
and you decided you're like
we're talking about earlier
like I don't want to
it's crazy because as soon as I
said I didn't want to
and I like put it on Instagram
I wanted to
right
it's like the devil's
advocate right
it's like but I realized that
I don't
like I don't want to
like what am I getting out of it
what how much money have I spent
how many nights don't I remember
how many things have I done
that I wouldn't have done sober
I mean how many times have I like
I'm like how am I alive sometimes
like the situations I get myself
into
and I just realize I'm like
I'm not leading by example
I don't want someone to
that's not
who I want people to be like
I don't encourage people to be
like that
I want people to be encouraged
by positivity
and self-love
and stepping out of your comfort
zone and just being you
and when I was drinking
or smoking
it wasn't it was me
but it wasn't like the person
that I wanted to be
right and you knew that
and you feel that next day
you wake up and you feel I was
getting sick after one beer
I was hungover right
I used to drink like a fifth
and show like beer and wine
and that mixed everything
and like
but I was getting sick
after one beer
yeah it's like it's constant
signals of like okay like
this isn't benefiting you anymore
soul and my temple
was no more
no more
and like I smell bad
you know you stink
and like your hair
and your skin
your pores just leak
different smells
when you're drinking and
I just didn't want to be that anymore
I'm not saying I won't ever drink again
because I mean like
I can't control the future
but it is my intention
to not drink
love it
that's great
yeah I'm glad I
I think a lot of people are age
it's such a societal norm
to drink
like me I've been drinking
since I was I think 14
same
um yeah
four locals
like in the back of the car
oh gosh
with all the caffeine too
yeah little did you know listener
a four loco used to kill you
yeah
they still do I think
but it is weird though
you know we don't
it's not like
oh everybody who drinks is bad
no that's exactly what I was gonna say
it's
sometimes you like
we get thrown into our life
like this light
like we're doing this thing
that everybody's been telling us to do
we're following
it's not like
we're like being crappy people
we're working during the week
we're doing whatever we need to do
and it's like you go enjoy yourself on the weekend
but sometimes you gotta be like
okay
when I'm on my deathbed
when I'm like okay I lived my life
to the fullest
because everybody wants that
everybody wants to say
like I've done
done the things I want to do in life
I've had the best days ever drinking
it's not that I disagree with it
like it's fun
but a lot of times we don't
I feel like we lack the
like
do I want to do this right now
like we
yeah
we lack being able to stop ourselves
and be like
I am kind of
planning just for the next weekend
aren't I
or
or whatever it may be
I think
well that's another thing too
is like we look so much forward
to the weekends
to get fucked up to not remember
why are we looking forward
to not remembering
because we don't want to feel
and we want to check the fuck out
why are we looking forward
to not remembering
our lives
because we're not happy
I always say
I like saying
like when you're
when it's late at night
and you've already been drinking
and you're like deciding to drink
more
or for me like when it would be
cocaine
when I'd be like
oh I'm gonna do cocaine tonight
I would always tell myself
well you're gonna do that
but you're making the choice
to borrow some happiness
from tomorrow
really
after like a lot of it
a lot of the times
a lot of our
weekend drinking
when it comes to like
oh it's been literally every weekend
this year
I drink
sometimes it's like
what am I borrowing happiness from
am I borrowing happiness
like weekend by weekend
from next year in my life
you know
not to mention of course
for me personally
I cannot drink without
having a burrito afterwards
I feel like
I was just gonna say like
I eat bad
oh man it just
it just comes with
and then the next day
I eat bad
and like
yeah because you're hung over
and you justify why
you should eat bad
you're hung over
and yeah
I think taking a look
at these things
is super important
and you know
against it
but it's just really like
is that what you want
or is it just so habitual
to work the Monday
through Friday
and then go out Friday
Saturday
because you don't like your week
right
you know what I mean
instead
why don't you look like
I can't wait to come home
meditate and
to just sit with myself
and like
read
you know what I mean
find different thing
and I think a lot of it too is
um
people don't know what to do
when they have free time
they can't just be
with themselves
with their partner
and just say
I have so many friends that
they're partners
and they can't like
be sober together
and they're like dating
they have to get drunk
you know
yeah
a lot of relationships
start from the bar
and start from getting drunk
together
and that's how we've always been
and that's how it is
I don't want to be around them
sober
because I don't like them
or I don't like myself
wow
yeah that's tough
that's like
a lot of partners
they just drink
and that's what they do
well with mine
my partner doesn't drink
so I was drinking by myself
I'm like this is dumb
yeah
but if you're like
wait do I like this
but if he was still drinking
I can't say I would be done
do you know what I mean
he was almost like that catalyst
where it's like
why am I drinking by myself
yeah it's like him
him doing that
kind of made you take a look at
like
do I want to do this
yeah
do I want to not do this
because he's over it
like he spent all of his life
you know
using substances to numb it out
and here I am still like
drinking by myself
at restaurants
and he's not
and like
I just realized too
like I was drinking so much
because I wasn't in control
and I could blame the alcohol for my actions
right
I was really mean when I'm drunk
right yeah like losing
losing the control
I think a lot of people
you talk to a lot of people
when it comes to alcohol
and you get down to it
a lot of times they'll say the sentence
why I'm just a control person
I feel like I hear that often
I'm a control person
because I say the same thing too
right
but uh
I think
a lot of alcohol sometimes
for me it seemed like it would shut
my mind down
like I would use
when I was working in a warehouse
or I would come home
and I'm like I'm just so
like
I can't sleep
and I'm so like whatever
and so
it's depressing
yeah and so you drink
and yeah
but it's uh
it's a touchy subject
because I know a lot of listeners
still drink
and nothing is wrong with that
I'm just on a different path
than a lot of people
and I'm aware of that
no doubt
but the people that I look up to
they don't drink
that's also nothing like Buddha
Gandhi
Mother Teresa
like the people that are my
muses
they don't
they didn't drink
and it's like
I'm trying to walk in these
not saying that I'm Buddha
or Gandhi
and Mother Teresa
because I'm not by any means
those are people that I look up to
if that's a reference
anybody just drew
from what you just said
they're insane
like I'm not saying I am these people
but these are the people
that I look up to
these are the people
that I see when I'm meditating
so it's like
I want to embody that energy
and these people weren't
they aren't doing those
kind of things
and I want to be more
like the people I look up to
right
and they weren't drinking
and I think that so many people
again it's a touchy subject
because like
you think that you're being attacked
you feel like you're like
well I have my reason for blah blah
and we all do
and that's so okay
like I am so
everybody has their vices
I've had mine
I have mine
I think like
you know we all have to experience them
in different things
but I think the biggest thing
is just having that moment
like I was saying
when I was driving in the car
and I'm like
oh I'm gonna take a left here
and I'm gonna like
I don't want to feel this anger
this road rage
so like when it comes time
to like sometimes just breaking
your habits of like
you're planning on going to the bar
on Friday or Saturday
and like just this weekend
don't go
and maybe say like
what do I actually want to do
like what
and if you think about it
it's like you know what
I mean I love snowboarding
I'm gonna go snowboarding
or I love
oh there's a
conference for this
computer program
that I like in Portland
I'm gonna go try that out
like just follow your interests
and follow
what you're drawn to
like so what
I spend a lot of my free time
is going to nurseries
or going to pet stores
or going to new parks
or going to new places
outside
or going into like boutiques
like because I like to see people's craft
you know what I mean
I like
Portland is like my place
like I love going into new stores
and I love going into plant
I love plants so
but it also inspires me
so doing these things
is inspiring me
and reminding me what I love
it's like when I walk
into a plant store
I'm like
like I just went to pollen
yesterday
flower store
I'm like oh my gosh
I love it
isn't it so
it's totally cute
they deck out like the outside
the paint of the outside
the interior
is always like
based off of different all days
it's just perfect
yeah it's great
but when you like something
you follow that
and it inspires you
so do things that inspire you
like if you want to open a bar
then yeah
and keep going to bars
like if that's like your dream
you love beer
and you want a brewery
go for it
but like if you want to do some
and that's something I also want to encourage people
you can do whatever you want to do
it doesn't matter
oh I've been working this job for 10 years
a little bit
it doesn't matter
whatever you want to do
you can stop and start and do it
it really it sucks in the beginning
because you're like
maybe not getting as much
like I'm leaving paycheck to paycheck
but I know that
financial abundance is coming
like it will happen
if you're not terrified
you're not having a miserable time
no because you know what
I was working as a nurse
and I hated my life
I was not happy
I wasn't who I was
not saying that
like I just need to better
protect myself
like I'm applying to the hospital
but it's like
I know it's short term
but I feel like
what was happening is like
I when I go into this job
I'm like I was gonna be there for six months
I was there for 10
so it's like I'm just like
and I started to hate
like the people I was helping
and I was like resenting it
and like
if you start to feel like that
I was like I need to quit
because this isn't good for the people
and so many nurses are burnt out
and they can't recognize that
and take that break for themselves
yeah and they need to
I mean nurses are definitely
that's something like
I feel like
to be honest with Shaley
I feel like more and more
I'm always like
trying to push her to like
make sure you're taking care of yourself
but we don't right
and yeah you know
but it's it's something that she's
more and more and more aware of it
and making sure she doesn't just
like hold everybody's stuff all day
and she puts it down
when she gets home
and it's important
but I think a lot of us need to
or a lot of us could benefit
from seeing that like
you know what I
maybe I don't want to do that
this time
and I want to follow this other intuition
yeah and I just like to say like
what did you want to do in your
kid
because yes
really what did you want to do with your
kid like
you know I want to do this
well you can do that
like my boyfriend like
oh my gosh
you know like the squirrel suits
that's literally what he wants to do
so I'm like
oh my I don't know how that's a career
but let's go for it
like let's start jumping out of
playing like he literally like
since he's little like he just
wants to like
jump out of shit
like adrenaline right
like that's what gets him alive
like this mundane like
he needs adrenaline
yeah that's awesome
part of being a drug addict
and using heroin
and everything you need that
heart pounding
so it's like he wants to do that
I'm like I don't know how that's a career
but let's go for it
yeah follow it
yeah and like
you just start by jumping out planes
and you just keep going
like maybe you can instruct people
how to jump out of planes
I don't know
but who am I to tell you that
your dream is dumb
that's another thing people like
you can't do that
right
why not
sometimes I think that
that when it comes like dreams
like we see a lot of
we mix up a lot of like
talent with dreams
a lot of like
oh well this person
I saw a video of this person
when they were six
and they were singing
so they've been born with that
talent
it's like you don't have to have like
something that you were born with
crazy talent
it's just what what did you love
what did you enjoy
what were you drawn to
a hundred percent
it's like it's not like how do I make
this full-time career right this
second
it's like no no
it takes time
yeah point yourself at it
and start walking
and just start doing it
and like
another thing I talk about
Oprah always says soulful
Sundays
the most important thing
you can give yourself is time
and I know you have time to
meditate
two minutes a day
I always tell people
you don't have time
how much are you on your phone
what's your screen time
yeah
every time you check
how you know what I mean like
you have the time
you're just not choosing to use
the time for what you want
because a lot of it is again
lack of self love
not feeling
I don't deserve this time
I don't deserve to do what I want
to do
because I'm not good enough
or my parents you know
that's how my
and it's like this cycle
and it's like
it's really time to break free
and to step into your power
yes
truly
just
yeah I feel like
I don't know
I feel like I just
it feels right
that's what I'm doing
it feels and it feels right
I feel like you are doing that
you're like embodying it
and you're going for it
and you said you had
3,000 people listening already
and you just started
yeah
yeah no
I just started
well and it's this like
you know
I was serious about it of course
but the podcast
it wasn't like
I'm gonna do a podcast
and that's my destiny
this sort of thing
but it definitely feels very like
like whatever comes after this
or whatever this leads to
or even if I do a thousand episodes
like it does feel very right
feels very correct
when I'm like
editing the audio for that
like doing it
yeah I
I'm reminded
I'm like oh okay like
and honestly it helps me
feel my own self-love
like a lot of people
you know
sometimes it's so profound
I'm like
it even tears me up sometimes
when I'm
when I'm recording podcasts
so they
they're telling me something
very emotional
if they're like
they open up to me
not only to me
but on my podcast
and on
like they trust me
to take what they have to say
and I'm gonna hold it
and and and present it
in whatever way you know
so it's
things just start feeling right
and I think believing that
that is possible
it's definitely a
a self-love technique
it's a
knowing that
you'll heal over time
and waiting and being patient
that
I always like to talk about
like Oprah was fired
from her job
fired
like Oprah
right
and she said it was the best thing
that ever happened to her
because she was not supposed to be there
a lot of people we look up to
their lives just didn't happen
they had to work for it
and they failed
but they learned
and they got back up
and they did it better
right
a lot of people we like here
and they're famous
and all this
it didn't just happen overnight
I mean some people
yeah their family is probably famous
like the Kardashians
but I mean like
a lot of other people
like they had to work for it
and they all
if you look at anyone
they do affirmations
they meditate
they visualize all these people
we look up to
do this shit
it's the secret
the movie
the secret
the book
like it's not a secret
like we have the power
well because you can
you can change your
because if you dive into a lot of those
you know
the movie the secret
like even on YouTube
they have so many
like motivational ones
and they're so cool
because
when you start listening to them
and you let it play
and you just stay open to it
it starts making so much sense
it really does
it starts
for me
because I used to
I would see those things
and not know anything about them
so I'd be like
I don't know what the fuck
a lot of attraction is
I'm going to sit in order
like not real
yeah but not that I would like
disbelieve it
or you know like totally just
absolutely do my best to not
believe it
but I would just ignore it
because I'm like that
that ain't me
but when you just
start learning about these things
and listening to them
and opening ears to them
a little bit
it's like
huh
it does help your beliefs
but I wanted to read something
because I kept going to this page
and I know
I don't know how long
I don't know how time works
I don't know
how much more time you want
no we're
we're totally good
as long as you
want to keep going
so it's called acceptance
and I went to this page yesterday
this book is called
The Little Book of Inner Peace
and it's
if you let go a little
you have a little piece
if you let go a lot
you will have a lot of peace
if you let go completely
you will have complete peace
that is so me
I have
I'm let go
let go
like let go
like I
I struggle with that
a lot
and it's something I'm working on
all the time
that's like my mantra
like let go
like I write it
and like I draw it
and I art
because it's like
I don't know
holding on to an emotion
or holding on to
the idea of
how I wanted something to go
because I'm a planner
and if it doesn't go my way
like why is it crushing me
oh my gosh
yeah
I find that even when I'll DJ
like a small bar
and I'm like
oh this isn't going very well
it's like
dude this is just a small bar
and these people like
they're just having
they're totally fine
this isn't a detrimental
but you put it on yourself
and you're like
I need to hold on to this
shame or whatever comes at you
yeah
like I've said
like my boyfriend's from Hawaii
so I'm like a time Nazi
like I have an internal clock
that's so on point
like I'm like it's 245
like any time of the day
and he's like
well I don't know
maybe it's like
one or noon
and I'm like let's go
like and he's always late
but really it's always on time
if you change your perception
because we always are on time
I'm like oh we're late
we're late we're late
and then it always happens
so where we show up right
on time as we needed to
maybe it's not
12 o'clock
12 o'clock like people like
but it's like
on time for the energy
on time for the traffic
on time for whatever
and the more and more I'm
letting go of my constant need
to control time
and get in the car at 1055
because we need to leave
right now because I map quested
it and it takes 23 minutes
to get there with traffic
it's like
whoa like let go
like it's okay to plan
but it's also like
it's a control thing
and it's like
that fear of the unknown
and like
just going with the flow
sometimes is really hard for me
yeah because I think
that a lot of times
we we misinterpret
what's really going on
because like
if you are rushing
and you're
irritated with yourself
irritated with your partner
you're late to this thing now
like of course
next time like try not to even
let that be an option
if that's really that important to you
but a lot of this
like you show up
okay you're on time
you're right on time
but you're stressed out
and you're not yourself
no exactly
and you're talking to a passenger
yeah
and it like
it
oh it like
feels me up
and to me
I took it so personal
like
like this
so what
what's happening with me
is we were sharing a car
for a long time
when we first got here
and it was so hard
to just let go
of that
and like I was
so
I have abandonment issues
so what would happen after school
is my mom would just
sometimes not show up
so it's like that sitting there
on the sidewalk
as a little kid
waiting for someone
who's never gonna come
so what was happening
is after work
he wasn't there
because I got off
different times
because I'm a nurse
right
so you never know
when you're done charting
or when you're done
with the last medicine
or last treatment
someone dies
hot
you know
you never know
what time you're done
so it's not like
I'll be here at five o'clock
every day
it's kind of like
I'm texting calling you
this is when I'm off
and you know
he's not from here
so if he's in Vancouver
because he's exploring
or like doing something
and then I'm like I'm done
he has to drive
to come get me
like a logical person
who could say
okay it's gonna take 25 minutes
but that fear
of no one showing up for me
it was triggering me
oh it came right back up
and I was like screaming at him
like how can you be late
like
but the thing is
it's the car would break down
or he'd like
he had to help some
inside of the road
there was
all these things
in the universe
that kept making him late
and he
can see it
he's like
until you heal
for me being late, it's gonna keep happening.
And it was, once I just like accepted it,
he was always on time and it never stopped.
But once, but it was triggering this inner child moment
where I was like my mom abandoning me.
And it was like deep heal, like a deep trauma
that I didn't even realize I had
of like someone showing up for me, you know?
And then like something else I struggle
with my relationship is every time we would fight
I would just tell him to leave.
Cause if in my mind, the way I grew up,
if you loved me left, cause my mom would just go and leave.
And to me, that's how I was showed love, you leave.
So to me it's like, why are you here?
You obviously don't love me cause you're here.
So we try to push people away cause it's like
if you have abandonment issues, it's like leave.
If you love me leave, why are you here?
And you're frustrated.
Cause it's what love means to me.
You need to make it to where it makes sense in my head.
That's what I learned.
But it's like now that you're here,
you don't love me cause you're here.
And it's like this messed up twisted abandonment issues
that I had to rewire in my brain.
And he was like, what, he's, I'm not leaving.
Like what are you talking about?
But I'm like being like a little child
and throwing tantrums.
And it's like, who is this?
I thought I was meta, I was like Zen and peaceful.
And then I'm like screaming and crying.
Like I'm five, six, seven years old.
Like it's just like uncontrollable.
And he was like, whoa, it's so heavy.
But it was like so healing because a normal relationship
would be like, what the fuck?
This girl is crazy and leaving,
but he could see it as you have trauma to heal.
And that's what we're doing for each other.
And there's a button that I just accidentally pushed.
Let's investigate.
What is this?
It's so cool that you're able to look at it,
not only together and be like, where can we heal this?
But just the fact that you're able to say now,
like I don't want to act like that's not me.
Like cause a lot of times we feel so much shame
behind our like outbursts are like,
that we don't really want to deal with the fact
that like, man, I was acting out of line.
And I think maybe this is why.
A lot of times we want to like, well,
of course I was acting out of line.
I had a bad day and I had this and blah, blah,
and you're never on time and all these things.
And we think that that is like an answer.
Like that's justification there.
But it's, there's much more we can look at.
I mean, you've been in a relationship for how long?
Nine years.
Yeah.
So much communication.
Oh my gosh, yeah.
And it's always improving.
Yeah.
It's always changing.
It's never ending.
And I think another thing is we don't like to,
oh, talk about my boyfriend and I fight.
We fight.
It's normal.
It doesn't mean we're not in love,
but it's not like fighting where it's like,
we're being mean to each other and putting each other down.
It's not that kind of like dirty fighting.
Yeah.
When people are like, they're like, here,
I know something that you personally feel
very uncomfortable about yourself.
I'm gonna throw it at you.
Like, I know you.
I've seen those kind of fights.
You know, I have friends that fight like that.
I'm like, yeah, that's not right.
That's not, that's, you know, that is there.
It's toxic.
It's very toxic.
And I think just noticing like, okay,
so if you're one of these people and that's happened to you
and your anger gets the best of you and whatever,
like if now, right, this conversation is like,
oh crap, maybe I do this.
Triggering something?
Yeah, and it does trigger something.
That's something that's being pushed up on again.
And you can, now when this happens again,
you're gonna have this little sliver, I bet.
That's gonna be like, hmm,
maybe I don't have to react like that.
I'm queen of talking about relationships.
I think I love being in a relationship.
It helps me grow.
It's a mirror.
I can learn more about, I love being in a relationship.
It shows me where I need to grow.
When you're by yourself, you're like, yeah, yeah, yeah,
but when you're living in a small quarter with someone,
you're like, ooh.
Because really like the person you're with
should make you better.
Or what's the point?
To me, the whole point of our relationship is to love
and help each other grow and grow individually,
but together at the same time,
kind of like a money tree, like this.
You know, and have the same visions
and encourage each other.
And like, if your partner isn't doing that for you,
like, I know this sounds like shitty,
but it's like, what's the point?
To me, in my relationship,
if they're not making you grow or pushing you
or supporting you and all they're doing
is thinking your ideas are dumb
and they're putting you down all the time,
is that really like what you want?
Cause I know so many women that are in shitty relationships
with people who put them down.
I hear some of the things that these men say
to my friends and I'm like, oh.
Yeah.
Someone you love the most is putting you down the most.
Like, oh God.
Do you think that a lot of people like so-
When you take the love you think you deserve, right?
Oh yeah, that's a rough one too.
That's definitely, I mean-
But these men, I just don't even know
if they know they're doing it or I don't know.
I think a lot of it is, you know, not that it's okay.
That doesn't matter if they make it okay,
but I think a lot of our, when we make fun of people
and the things that we say in the, you know-
Well, men being feminine too
and expressing their feelings is like taboo.
I mean, yeah, my whole life has definitely been,
I've been beat up by Rednecks growing up.
I've always been, so like in Kelso for as far as,
as far as what I was aware,
I was probably too focused on myself, right?
But like in high school, I was like,
oh, I'm the first guy to wear the tight pants.
I'm the first guy to try a red eyeliner
and see who says anything about me.
I'm the first guy to dye my hair pink.
He sort of, like, I probably wasn't really, but-
Even your mind.
Right, but-
But to feminine.
Yeah, but you see how other people react.
Or trigger.
And they hate it and a lot of guys like,
I say Rednecks, beat up by Rednecks.
That's just a term that around here,
a lot of people, you know, drive a Toyota,
work in a lumber mill, you know,
these sort of personality types.
But a lot of times I would notice,
it's not so much that they're trying to make fun of me
as much as it's like an unawareness
that they are making fun of me.
They don't realize what they're saying.
And it's also like they're scared
that you can embrace your, like a feminine energy.
Oh yeah.
And when you see, when you are an alpha male
and then an alpha male who's feminine walks into that room,
you feel very shivery.
Yeah, it's weird and it's crazy
because like, same with females,
like when females, like, I remember when like girls
would wear like short skirts and that triggered me.
Like who are, you know, when I was like in high school,
like who are you to like dress like that?
But really she's just like, she's comfortable in her body
and she should be able to wear what she wants.
And it doesn't-
That doesn't affect you.
Yeah, why doesn't it?
But it triggers you
because you're not open like that to do it yourself.
For me, like, or, you know,
people who are getting ready all the time or, you know,
I'm like, oh, like, that's, you know, I don't get it,
but it doesn't mean that it doesn't bother me.
Like I don't care.
It's just not me.
But people who are like more feminine
and like like to do their eyelashes and their hair
and their makeup, nothing's wrong with that.
But like, I was like, I just never have been like that.
But it doesn't matter.
Yeah, you don't have an opinion on it.
No.
Even if you do it every day-
Doesn't make me better or less.
Yeah, you don't have to see other people
as wearing makeup or not wearing makeup.
No, I don't even see that anymore.
It's just them being them.
Yeah, I think we're like the more you,
the more you like meditate and the more you,
for me, it was definitely staying away from social media.
You start to like realize that like the things
that you held on to, like your judgments
about other people, they float away to where like,
you don't even remember that you had them at some point.
Like you're just talking to someone
and then I don't know, you wouldn't even notice
something like if they're wearing a ton of makeup,
you wouldn't notice that if you did before.
No, and I just think like this area is super,
I don't know, but like it's,
I don't feel like a lot of people are truly
stepping into their authenticity and being themselves
because we mask it with a lot of things.
Cause I feel like a lot of us do the same things every day.
We go to the, there's like two bars or,
you know, there's not a lot of do in this town
or you know, we do this,
we have the same friend group forever.
And I feel like it's really uncomfortable
for people to step out of that comfort zone
and go explore and be by themselves
and like meet new people or move.
I mean, I moved to Hawaii and I'm back.
Like something is here, you know,
but I feel like I'm here to like help people
in the area for some, I'm here for a reason.
Like we all are, like we're here
in this weird ass town for a reason, right?
Yeah, it's funny cause like I, you know,
you grow up and you have your opinions
at different places.
So like Redneck for example, that word would affiliate
the town that I live in now, Castle Rock,
I would affiliate as a younger kid,
this town with Rednecks.
Oh, there's Rednecks living up there.
And then you grow up and you learn like,
oh, that's just a couple of people
that I saw that affiliated a whole town with it.
Yeah, for sure.
I think, you know, I, you know,
traveling around for work and stuff throughout the years
I was always, I wanted to get away from here.
Like I was like, I wanna move out somewhere
with the sunshine and now it's like,
I just understand things differently
and I'm like, I love it here.
And there's, it's so interesting,
like right in between Seattle and Portland.
And the desert and the ocean
and the mountains and the mountain, the forest.
Right, and I, just the places that you can go,
it's a spectacular place.
We are literally in the most perfect place.
Like we can literally go to Portland.
We can go to like anywhere we want.
It's cheap to fly out of Portland.
Like it's the best airport in the country.
Like we just have so much around us.
And I think we just sometimes get stuck in our town.
I'll notice, I'm like,
when's the last time I left woodland?
It's been a week.
Like sometimes you get stuck
and I need to go to Portland and reset
and like feel that creative energy.
We have so many different things
that we can reset with here is the best thing.
Like you can, if you want to go to waterfall, cool,
an hour away, if you want to get the ocean,
cool, an hour and 20 minutes away.
If you want to go to the mountain, cool.
45 minutes, all these things.
I think instead of doing the exact same things
every weekend and keep doing these the same weekend
and the same whatever, living over,
try to, try to see what's around you.
I mean, a lot of our listeners
are probably people that I know for the most part.
And I just want to say that like,
I love everyone that I've met.
Everyone that I partied with would do so much
have helped me so many times.
I see the creative and I see the light
and like I think of Adrienne right away.
Like I love Adrienne, I love you if you're listening.
And like I think of, and always smiling,
like I just think of so many people
and like Bailey Keegan, like I just,
there's so many people in this town that I just like love
and they're just so full of light
and just it's amazing how we all are here.
And I feel like we're all here everywhere.
Like there's a bunch of these towns that are like this.
It's just that lack of connection.
Like we don't get to see each other
in like a sober way.
That's why I want to create like a space
where we can just like hang out and like talk.
Well, I think that we have like this cool potential
for this thing.
Cause we know, like the names that you just said,
like we know a lot of times we know
so many different names from the parting,
from the, whatever, like me for a good reason.
But like it's a we party together for a reason.
Yeah, we're all connected.
And now it's like we have this thing
where we can stay in touch.
We don't have to like,
we can be friends throughout life.
Like we've got 40, 50 more years.
Like I'm probably going to see you again, you know?
And I can say, how are you?
And you could say I'm good.
And we, you can say I used to live this life
and that's how we met.
But now I live this different life
and we're still friends
and you can compare your life to each other.
Inspires me daily.
And like I've always loved him, always vibed with him.
Like I'm so happy and stoked for what he's doing
because he's such a catalyst in his story for our town.
Like you can do it.
And I see his stories all over the country.
Like when he was saying like Hawaiian Arizona,
I'm like, I see it.
Like it's not even like,
like he's planting the seeds
and all our brains to be creative.
I love what he's doing.
Dude, you walk into a store
and he plants a seed for sure.
All of his guys do.
And it's just like that,
but it's in our town for a reason.
Like we're just surrounded by these creative beings
and not everyone stepped into it.
Not everyone knows,
but it's like nothing's random.
Like we all have this intercosmic soul family web
where we are friends with all of each other
and web, web, web.
We know this person,
know this person.
It's like we're all supposed to create this new world.
It's so, it's,
now I'm the one getting chills.
It's so exciting.
I just keep getting,
it excites me to think like my mind,
I think a lot of it is it's a rushing in
of like thinking and giving myself a future
because I had so many like,
I'm going to end things sort of thoughts
for so many years that like,
I think of like, okay,
here's my connections that I know all these people
like think about the people you just named off.
They're so awesome.
And it's like,
oh yeah, in like going forward in life,
like we're going to have interactions
and we're going to be able to build
these things together and it's very exciting.
Because they're good people.
We are so blessed.
Like, you know,
yeah, there was like some minor drama,
but like at the core,
like those people would be there for you.
No doubt.
If you called them, like they would come.
At least, I hope,
at least I believe in my heart,
but I just feel like those genuine like party connections
like, yeah, we're all fucked up,
but there's a reason we kept partying together
all the time.
Any house, this house, this house,
who's here, you're here.
I was at that party,
you're at that party like swings, house, tires,
like we were all at these same parties
and it was like a reason we were all
and all of us probably had trauma.
Well, that's why we're drinking at 13, 14 years old.
The amount of people that I mean,
the serious probably crying conversations
that I've had just at parties,
like sometimes you just get a little drunk
and you're talking with someone who just
understands what you're saying.
You get into it.
I mean, did you grow up,
excuse me, when you were like in high school,
did you party in high school?
I did.
Yeah.
Cause I like,
it's super interesting.
I'm 28.
Okay, I'm 24, so it was like.
Oh yeah.
But yeah, still probably similar things
like around here, like you,
I don't know if it's different like California
if they party at the beach or something,
but we definitely go to like house parties.
And it's a, you know, a lot of the,
like the amount of serious, wonderful,
very smart conversations I've had
at an outdoor glass table.
Yeah.
Like that outdoor glass table.
Like in, it's cool.
Like these are kind of like that.
Yeah.
I should get a glass table in here.
That's just a full of mold.
But you know, it's like those girls
that always have like the bathroom,
you know, the bathroom line story,
the girls that meet people in the bathroom
when they come best friends.
It's so true though.
Like I just feel like that's where I'm at now,
but in a sober way,
in a way that I just wanna like,
I want you to just freaking go for your dreams.
Like I just like, go for it.
Like anyone that's listening,
like just go for it.
Because like you can do anything you want.
And I just like, well, I see people,
I'll question people.
I'll be at a gas station,
like what do you wanna do for a living?
And they'll tell me and I'm like,
why aren't you, go for it.
And people don't get questioned enough.
Question people in your life,
what are you doing?
Do you wanna do this?
Why don't you change?
Yes.
I might bother them.
I might trigger them.
I'm like, do something.
Yes.
Why not?
Tell people to do something.
And be encouraging.
Encourage people.
Yeah, you wanna be rude about it,
but like, I'm like, wake up.
Like I just want everyone to like see
how beautiful they really are.
And like just see like how wonderful the world is.
And like, sometimes like it's gonna be hard to do
when you're not feeling good or depressed,
but like, just like,
if you can do that for someone else
and it can come back
and like just be compassionate always.
That's like my main thing is like be compassionate.
Like I had to write down my five values the other day
and I was like, compassion is like my number one.
Injustice, equality, love and empathy.
So it's like, what are your five values
and are you embodying those every single day?
I think a lot of people don't even ask
what their values are.
I mean, I didn't for a very long time.
Yeah.
You didn't tell more until, you know,
again like two years ago.
Yeah.
And now it's like my life is better
like knowing that I, you know,
maybe I'm still circling some of them, I think.
But I think like solidifying them
and allowing myself to have them is good values.
I think it's just hard to be human
but there's people around you
that are going through the same thing.
No doubt.
And probably your neighbor, literally.
Right.
You think they're judging you
for wearing pajama pants outside?
They're just going through their own shit too.
Yeah.
And like I think to take things like lighter
and to just be more kind and gentle with yourself
and to not be so hard on yourself.
Cause I'm so hard on myself.
I write a to-do list every day
and I put 50 things on it and I do four
and I'm like, oh man, my days suck.
But really it's like, it didn't.
Right.
I just have these high expectations
and then when I don't meet them,
I like am down and I'm like, but I did something.
I wasn't just sitting all day
and it's like, but I felt like I wasn't doing anything
and I were like reflect and I'm like, what did I do?
You know, but I wasn't just doing nothing.
So it's like.
You, yeah, you're working towards it.
You see yourself as as higher like,
I know that I am capable one day
or you know, something like,
I'm going to do these things.
I'm going to get all 12 things done
but I did do four today and that's so great.
Yeah.
You know, like give it, the reflect is a great word.
I think a lot of people,
a lot of times we have so much momentum,
so much forward movement in our lives
that we don't give ourselves time to reflect.
Like, I'm not, maybe I'm not living my dream right this day
but like I did good today and that's, that's cool.
Like give yourself that.
Because I struggle with that like, oh, like, you know,
for example, and think the crazy thing is like,
I've been enrolled in herbal school for like almost a year
but I can't, I have not done it.
Why am I holding myself back?
It's almost like I'm scared to step into my light.
So like I don't feel deserving to be living my dream job.
So that's where the deserving comes in.
So it's like, yeah, I took that step
and I'm paying for it every single month
but why am I not taking the time to do it for myself?
And it all stems from the lack of I don't deserve to do this
or I'm not going to make enough money
or what do I know or I'm not good enough.
And it's crazy because it's like this constant battle
where herbal school is on my schedule is every single day
but it's like, I'm not doing it.
And that's like, I'm just need to do it.
And I was like, we went to the hot springs the other day
and I'm like, I want to go to naturopathic school
and my way friend's like,
you're not even doing the school you have now.
He's like, why are you trying to add things to your play,
add things to your play, add things to your play
and then you're not even doing the things
that are on your play.
It becomes too much.
You have too many options.
But I like being like that.
It's so weird.
It's novelty, I think.
Sometimes I feel like I'm so fascinated
by fucking everything that I just want to be a professional
in all the areas of it that I can somehow.
Yeah, like my biggest thing,
my biggest goals are to do a blog
and have a YouTube channel.
I don't know what it is exactly
but I just know that I need to speak.
I know with my Instagram, it's social media
and when I quit doing it,
because you struggle too with your mind and social media
but to me, I get off and I'm like, oh, I feel good
but then it's like, I need to speak
because my videos, people are like, thank you.
I needed to hear this.
I'm feeling the same way.
I can't tell you how many times I do videos
and people are like, I have someone from Bulgaria
that I've met, New Zealand, Australia,
like all over the South Africa,
women from all over the world finding me
and they're like, I feel you 100%, thank you.
Yeah, and how do they find you?
Like, whatever happened in their life
to stumble upon you is so sick.
Seriously, these women, I'm like,
and they're going through the same thing.
They're feeling, I feel you all the way from here,
like Bulgaria, Bulgaria, I'm like, what?
And she's like, I feel like we're sisters
and it's so crazy because I'm talking to these women
and I have so much in common with them
and they're across the world.
But it's a collective shift
and people are tuning into it
and that's how I feel like my Instagram
is like tuning into like my show.
Yeah, I think you're, of course,
if you feel yourself drawn into it,
like take a step back
but I think your Instagram is great.
You should definitely keep going.
I also, and we can talk about this afterwards too.
So that's my plan.
I have a YouTube channel
and I have the podcast uploaded.
I eventually want to have video episodes
so that'll add to it
but I also have a few,
like sometimes I'll have pretty clear thoughts
while I'm out hiking or something
and I'm like, I'm gonna try to talk to the camera
for 10 minutes.
So I have a couple of those up there
but my plan, I actually would like to start making
like a weekly blog or a monthly blog something,
writing myself.
So we should maybe try to fuel each other on that.
Maybe text each other every few weeks
and be like, hey, how are you doing on that?
We should-
Well, it's crazy because it's like a collective shift.
I'll get these crazy ideas and thoughts
that just download into my brain
and I'll talk to my partner and he's like, same.
So it's crazy.
I'm vegetarian and yesterday I ate meat.
It's just so weird.
But I was ashamed.
I was like, cause I haven't eaten meat.
How long has it been?
Like I've been vegetarian for like three years.
I've like, but yesterday I just like, I don't know why
but like this piece of sausage, like it looks so good.
I'm like, what the hell?
Like I love animals.
So I'm like, and then I talked to my boyfriend.
I'm like, I have a confession.
And I was like, he's like, what?
I'm like, I had a piece of sausage.
He's like, that's so weird.
I had a chicken sandwich yesterday.
He's vegetarian too.
And I'm like-
I'm like, it's-
I wonder about that.
Like, what is that?
You know, like-
I don't know.
He's like, I didn't feel good.
I only had blah, blah, blah.
I'm like, he's like the only thing there was
and like whatever and like, there was more food.
But it's so weird.
And it's just, I think when we label ourselves
we get, feel ashamed.
Like, I'm a vegetarian and I eat an animal.
Like I'm a bad person.
It's like, no, we make mistakes.
But it's like, I obviously like,
I'm like must be low on iron or something
or maybe I'm not getting all what I need.
Or maybe it's just a reminder of why I don't eat me
because it doesn't make me feel good.
Or, you know, sometimes we need those slip-ups
to be reminded of why we're doing it in the first place.
Right.
Yeah, okay.
So I wanna just to be conscious of your time.
I want to, because you're talking about eating healthy.
I feel like you have-
I'm pretty plant-based.
Yeah, I feel like you have some great advice.
So I just, let's just take the last 15 minutes
or so here.
And let's just talk about you being an herbalist
and talk about-
Not yet, but yeah.
I just wanna, I feel like you have knowledge
in the outdoors.
And I'm so, I'm very intrigued by obviously anything diet-wise
or like how things go into the body as far as nature.
But I'm just very much, I haven't fully ex-
You want me to tell you why I'm vegetarian?
Cause I would love to.
Yeah, let's do that, yes.
So it all started when I was at summer camp.
I'm like, I'm just gonna tell everyone I'm vegetarian
even though I wasn't, but I'm prideful, right?
So it was crazy cause 20 of the camp
counts were vegetarian.
So it was just like a vibe.
And I was like, I'm just gonna say I'm vegetarian.
And once I say that, I'm prideful, I'm not gonna eat meat.
So that's how I was able to fully stick to it.
If I was living on my own,
I don't know how it would have transformed into me
not eating meat.
But since I was placed in a camp situation
where I wasn't able to choose my food,
but everyone else was looking at what I was eating
cause I said I was vegetarian.
So that's how I was able to fully embody
like not eating meat and move to Hawaii and eat fish.
So I haven't been full, okay, it's pescatarian,
but I don't really eat fish anymore.
But the reason I really, really chose to stop
is because I look at a pig or a chicken or a cow
with the same love that I do when I look at my partner
because it's, they're, they're alive.
And they have, to me, I feel their energy
and their soul and their heart beating.
And like, I don't know, like,
I don't feel like I'm any better than animals or bugs.
I've never killed a bug.
Like, this is just me.
I'm very empathetic.
And I just, I have dreams of like factory farms.
And like, I just, you know, growing up around cows,
like I, you know, I just couldn't imagine like killing
and like, I see them on the, on the trucks and I cry.
And I'm like, personally, I couldn't kill an animal.
So I feel like I don't deserve to eat it for me.
What was happening is I would be eating a hamburger
and I was sad.
I would start to cry.
And I asked one of my spiritual teachers what's going on
and she's like, well, you're taking on the fear
of that animal.
So think about how scared these animals are
when they're dying, right?
And then think about the people killing the animals.
They don't like what they're doing for the most part.
They're happy unhappy with their job.
They're usually immigrants
and they're low energy people killing the animal.
And think about how long the animal's been dead.
So you're eating like dead flesh
and it just freaked me out and all the bugs in it.
And then the, and then the colors in that.
And then how long has it been dead?
And you can watch any videos
that'll just definitely, yeah.
And nothing again.
And that's another thing.
People that's like vegan or die.
I don't want, I don't believe in pushing it on people.
It's super like, I believe in the blood type thing too,
which is a different thing.
But I just felt in my heart that I could do it
without animals.
And I just felt like I loved animals so much.
And when I look at my cats, like other countries eat cats
and I'm like, how could they eat a cat?
How could they eat a dog?
And it's like we eat everything.
Right.
It's just different.
It's, it's so weird.
I think that we're so disconnected from
the way food is processed.
Well, like I always talk about like we eat nuggets.
You know, you're eating a chicken.
You know, we change the names of the food.
We're eating pepperoni, reading salami.
What animal?
I don't even know what animal I'm eating.
I don't, I'm eating like meatloaf.
Like what is like, you know, we're not really taught.
We're not associated.
So we as children, we don't associate the meat
with the animal we're eating.
We'll change it into something else
because I guarantee you, like I told them,
like if we have kids and they want to eat meat,
they have to kill it themselves.
And if they can't kill it, they don't get to eat it.
Maybe that's crazy.
But I'm like, because if you gave me that option
as a kid.
You just raised some savage who's out there just hunting.
That's like whole day.
Like we're going to grow a sociopath.
He's like five just damn.
I brought home this deer mom.
He dragged it.
We talked about that too, but I just feel like
I can't kill it, so I don't deserve to eat it.
And I so empathetic in my powers just grow daily
that I was literally feeling the fear
of these animals in my body.
And I was scared and my anxiety was bad.
And I have friends who are vegetarian
and they go back to eating meat
and their anxiety gets bad.
And I also think about energy, right?
So if you think that you're eating something
that literally was alive and it's been dead,
so you're eating something that's dead
and you want to feel alive, explain that to me.
Yeah.
And so something else that's really interesting is
so steak sits in your stomach for three days.
So imagine like a 98 degree hot,
went Washington day and you throw a steak on the sidewalk.
How would it look and smell and feel?
That's what's happening inside your stomach.
And then it take, you'd think our intestines
are really long, like football field long.
And then this piece of meat is like dragging along
in your intestine and it's like cutting off
and it's breaking off and it stays in there.
And we don't digest it very well.
Animals who eat meat, their intestines
are way shorter than ours.
Like way shorter, like six, 10 feet shorter
than ours the way they absorb things.
So they have to eat meat and they eat it raw too.
They don't cook, you don't see cheetahs
like cooking their meat on like a stove.
Like we don't eat it raw.
I'm just really into the raw thing
where I feel better when I eat vegetables and fruit.
I feel more alive, like the vibration.
Like I can, I like simple ingredients.
So I like to think like who farmed my food,
the energy of my farmer.
Like was it a happy farmer?
Totally.
Or is it someone at McDonald's who hates their life
and they're putting hate into your food
and then you're putting the energy into your body.
I totally feel that, cause I think the same way.
Yeah, I think that there's more of, you know,
when you, so say you go to like a farmer's market
down the road from your house or something,
like you have this interaction with this person.
You can see who grew your food, it's so crazy.
And they tell you about it and they're like,
oh yeah, my, you know, my family's owned a honey farm
for my whole life and then there's some honey
and whatever.
And it's kind of what you're leaning towards creating.
One of me, my family's are farmers,
you know, Segao nurseries, Segao farms.
Like that's how we started.
But it's also just like being connected to your food.
I am very passionate about that.
Like, where's your food come?
Oh, I get so crazy.
Like when my QEs are from New Zealand,
like how long ago was that picked?
And then the process of getting here
and just like I, one day I wanna like,
that's why I love to why so much.
Cause I'm eating like off the trees
and it just feels so right.
But when we're eating food that's been picked
or dead for a while and you,
it's hard to feel good with your food.
You know, we're so disconnected
from our food and the process.
Yeah, I think another time people don't realize
how draining their food is cause they don't really
aren't in tune with their body.
But like this morning, my boyfriend brought home
cause he sometimes not very good.
He brought home like, I love potatoes.
He brought home a hash brown and I ate it
and I instantly felt sick and I had to go meditate
and like do a tarot and like,
I went and bought a juice to like make up for it.
Cause I like felt like greasy and like low energy
and like, I don't eat McDonald's.
Like I don't like McDonald's.
Like why did I do that, you know?
Yeah.
I think exploring what your body feels like.
So when you first started, when you're like, okay,
like this is obviously affecting me eating this meat.
When you started switching to just,
just whatever you went to.
What was that?
Like, do you remember those first couple of months?
Was there like mental cognition increase?
It's hard because like I like quick fast food.
Like I liked fast food.
Like I used to freaking go to Taco Bell McDonald's
in one drive through setting.
Like, I love Taco Bell.
Yeah, same.
I like ate Taco Bell the other day.
I just like get no cheese or meat.
Not that it's the best, but I just feel like, I mean,
it's a vibe.
Like another thing I want to care, like stress
is consumers control, like since there's almond milk,
the dairy consumption has gone down so much.
Like dairy farms are getting shut down all over the country
because we don't need it as much
because consumers control it.
So it's like, another thing I'm really passionate about
is we're cutting down acres of the Amazon
to graze more cow.
So that's another thing.
It's the environment.
And then I also think how many gallons of fresh water
are we wasting on these livestock?
The fresh water crisis don't even get me started on.
Well, we also soil only has so many year,
like you can't, if you just keep digging up
the same farm every year.
Well, that's why they have to keep grazing
and cutting down more and more forest, old forest,
forest that has been there longer
than we can think to graze more animals
for a temporary satisfaction doesn't vibe with me.
And for what I, like when I wrote out my mission goal
and like my life statement, my purpose
and why I'm here is to save the planet.
So to me, saving the planet starts
with what I put into my body and consumer.
And, you know, once I started going vegan,
I was like, oh my God, there's feathers in my blanket.
How'd they get here?
And my mom goes, they pluck them from ducks alive.
And I just think about like the, like we don't think
about it.
And we disconnect ourselves from those things.
Yeah. And like, I just like, oh my gosh.
Like I wanted, and like there's leather and like
everything and like I just, well, what was happening
though is I was getting so crazy.
Like every, we were on a road trip
and I was like in Vegas and I was like crying
because of just like, you can see the consumption
and like the resources.
And I'm just like, people just don't see it
and it's not their fault.
But like, I like tear up thinking about it.
It's just like, we are draining the earth so hard
and all she does is like love us.
Right. I think that the important thing though
is you see it and other people's don't.
And that's not so much of like, they're all bad.
It's like, okay, I see it.
So like, I gotta, I guess teach them, you know?
And that's what seems to be here doing.
I mean, like if you think of like indigenous people
they worship the ground.
They stomped on the ground.
They worship the sun.
They pray to the water like.
Do you, do you have speaking of, I just wanna touch on that
because like you probably have good,
I'm big on grounding for me.
It's like, so when I get off a plane, I get home
and I'm like, I go in the back.
Of course I love to have a joint of company with it
but take off my shoes and I'll stomp around.
All, all, if I feel like doing yoga
and just rolling around in my grasp.
You know the science behind that?
Yeah, I do a little bit, but I'd love for you to.
So the way that works is you,
there's free ions in the earth energy on the ground
and it's like there's abundant amounts.
So when you are on balance, there's something,
the free ions, you have shockers on the bottom of your feet
and sometimes they can get clogged or not ground.
When you start to walk on the grass, they start to open up
and then these free ions literally enter
through the bottom of your feet
and ground you and connect you.
Yes.
You'll notice you're grounded.
People who can't stand on both feet
are like kind of on one foot, other foot, like me.
You're not, both feet are on the ground,
it means you're ungrounded.
You can see that all the time
or if you're leaning one way or leaning the other
or your feet don't touch the ground or you're ungrounded.
And being ungrounded is something I'm working on every day
because I'm really ungrounded.
Right, okay, so what's your technique for grounding?
Mine is definitely just walking around like.
Well, like same thing, like definitely walking outside,
definitely like grounding meditation.
So like an easy way to ground is like think of a root
coming from like the bottom of your like sit bone
and like put it deep into the earth
and it just everything like releases
and releases and releases and then take up earth energy
and bring it up, you know, out through your head,
connect with the sky and then bring it back
and create like this chronic like in and out
and flux of energy.
Yeah, yeah, it's like one continuous thing.
Even though you can't see it,
like you can envision it and it's happening, you know?
People like, oh, I don't see auras.
I have a lot of friends who see auras
and that's their gift, I have different gifts.
You know, I wanna see aura, I wanna see energy
just cause you can't see it doesn't mean it's not there.
You know, I think of dogs hear sounds,
we don't hear it doesn't mean the sound isn't there.
We just can't hear it cause we're not in that frequency.
Same with energy, it's the same thing.
And I think, I think a lot of visualization
tunes us into, you know, almost like a tricking
of your brain, like a lot, for me,
a lot of feeling these things
and like connecting with them
is following guided meditations.
And like in so, so guided meditations, for example,
they'll tell me, I just recently listened to one
that just said the same thing you did.
Imagine a root coming from, you know, your root chakra,
your butt rather, you push it through the ground
and through these things, like through the meditation,
I follow it, I give into it, I, they say,
envision your roots going through the ground
and feeling the dirt and you feel that.
And you say, what would it be like in my head?
What would it be like right now
if I did have roots coming out of my body
and just grabbing into the earth?
Yeah.
Well, I know, and that's the thing is
if you believe it and you allow yourself to feel it,
it's profoundly healing, you know, a lot of these,
I don't know, I always just think of like
that person who sits down and they hear that,
like imagine a root going through the ground
and the person's like, what the fuck are you talking about?
I always like bringing that up
because I used to be one of those people, I feel like.
Yeah.
Another thing, sorry, I know we're really getting close,
but like those of you who say you can't meditate
are the ones who need to meditate the most.
I'm so, I love, yeah, I repeat that again.
Those who say they can't meditate
are the ones who need to meditate the most.
What advice do you have for those people?
I think that when you start,
you're gonna hear a lot of thoughts and it's okay,
you don't have to be an expert.
Like when I first started, I literally was like,
nope, turn off, I can't sit still with my thoughts,
but I can be on my phone for hours mindlessly.
I started with Headspace, it's a great free app.
There's a 10 minute guided one and just,
I also recommend doing the same meditation every day.
So, because you start to get ready for the words
and the music sounds the same and like,
it's like a two minute,
there's two minute ones on YouTube.
And what you learn is you start to listen to it
and your brain is a muscle and you're training it
so you hear that music and you're like,
I know what to do, time to relax.
And you grow and you grow and you grow
and you grow and eventually you can do it longer
and you do it longer and you do it longer
and it just happens, it doesn't happen overnight.
You can, I'm gonna do an hour meditation today.
No, if you don't meditate, please don't do that
because you're just gonna get frustrated and fail.
Yeah, you're gonna see it as this giant staircase
and I'm gonna wanna take another step tomorrow.
I have a Facebook right back created called Love and Light
and I'm just like, literally,
here's a two minute meditation.
Beauty.
You can do it when you get home from driving from work.
That's enough to reset you.
I mean, you could feel, two minutes of closing your eyes
and connecting with something that feels real
and feels soft and comfortable.
And if you don't like people talking at you,
I listen to whale sounds a lot.
Hell yeah, whale sounds, I'm all down for whale sounds.
Or like the Amazon rainforest or anything natural,
doesn't always have to be guided.
If you just need to be sit,
you can listen to nature sounds or something,
whatever floats your boat.
Or if it's instrumental, I also love Mozart and piano
and that kind of stuff too.
So it's whatever you can do to quiet it.
We totally listened to a lot of the same stuff
because a week ago, I was listening to whale sounds
for a while.
Yeah, we were like, what the hell am I listening to whales?
It's an option on Spotify.
How can you not click on it?
I was like, I saw it, I was like, what?
Well, I dream of whales a lot.
So I just felt like, yeah, I felt super.
I don't think that I do.
Yeah, I dream about being underwater a lot
and like breathing underwater.
Like I'm like living in the ocean a lot.
Really?
So I actually have a, it's weird.
I don't know if it's fear.
So I have a little bit of fear of water.
Yeah, me too.
I think I had a moment.
I think I had like a traumatizing experience.
Like tubing when I was younger.
Right.
Hey, maybe that's what it was.
But I do, I feel also a drawing,
a connection to water.
I feel like-
Well, I'm past love water.
Really?
Yeah.
Okay, because when I go, so Cold Water Lake,
for example, is one of my favorite places is,
and you know what I read yesterday?
Actually, I had no idea it wasn't there
before 1980 when the volcano.
Yeah, it's a new lake.
Yeah, I had no idea.
But I feel very, you go there and there's a scare,
but there's also this like connection to the water.
It's like a little scary and dark, but-
But your fears are like, I have the fear of like,
I'm in the lagoon and something's gonna pull me down.
And like, that's irrational.
But I feel like it, I'm like, oh, like what's down there?
You know, you're like swimming faster
and it's like, what is that?
It's irrational and you just like,
Yeah.
I've got fear go.
I'm like, what is that?
Honey!
It feels like we're in water.
What's this?
It says something you bring to town at the same time.
fear like has been holding me back
from like reaching my full potential.
And I think for me like it's truly scary
to like step into the light
because a lot of people aren't there
or doing it and whom I am 24 year old
like from the small town
but we are like magnificent beings
and like we all have this in us.
It's just everyone's at different stages of it.
Absolutely.
I mean, I think you're magnificent
and I feel like being able to like
the fact that I had no you
and I can have you on my podcast
and this is like what's creating itself
and it's just a wonderful thing.
Thank you for having me.
I appreciate it and like just creating this space
to have like conversations
and I feel like your intentions are so pure
and it really like shines through.
And I think that's why you are,
the listeners are growing
because they can like feel it.
You don't have like this interior motive
to make all this money,
which is nothing wrong with that
but I can feel like your intentions
like shine through and the listeners can like feel that.
It's like for them, you know,
but it's for you with the same time
and it's like to help people at the same time.
It is.
And it honestly feels it's very fulfilling
and it just feels right.
Like I don't know much more than that.
It just feels super right and it feels good.
I enjoy doing it
and I know whatever is going to come from it
is going to be what I need to do.
You know?
It's just so obvious.
So let's just round about shout out your Instagram.
Let's make sure everybody knows where to find you.
You're a wonderful person to follow on Instagram
and that's for sure.
And then in the future,
you can also work on YouTube channel.
Yes.
More stuff.
We can even have more podcast episodes.
That would be great.
Yeah, I would love to.
It's Celestial Gypsy Witch.
But I guess we can probably post it on your page
underneath or something.
Definitely.
But yeah, I feel just super honored to be here
but I just really want,
if you're still listening to this,
like to realize like you are here for a reason
and I think you aren't probably told that enough.
I really feel like that.
People aren't told that enough
that you are here for a reason
and you are needed and you are loved.
You are needed, you are loved
and you are here for a reason listener.
Absolutely, I agree with you.
It was such a great conversation.
Yeah, thank you so much.
Thank you.
Have a good rest of your day listeners.
Drink some water, take care of yourself.